<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Mugo - Commercial</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:56:47 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (Mugo Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>National Bank of Georgia HQ</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/national-bank-of-georgia</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/national-bank-of-georgia</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/erovnulibanki/banki-fasadi.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Concept</span></h4>
<p>The main concept of the new Headquarters of the National bank of Georgia project is the synthesis of its shape, aesthetics, ideology, and the function.</p>
<p>The ideology of the building is guided to its geometric shape of the circle, which is considered to be a continuous source of eternity and constant existence.</p>
<p>The ideal shape of the circle is associated with sustainability and the analytical nature of the function of the National Bank, which is linked to the country's economic development and stability.</p>
<p>The outer diameter of the circle is 60 meters while the inner diameter is 28 meters, which forms an internal atrium of the building.</p>
<p>The glass skylight, what tops the atrium is represented by the National Bank’s logo, which once again highlights its direct connection to the function of the building.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Context</span></h4>
<p>In establishing the functional and architectural character of the project, the concept of determining energy efficiency criteria plays one of the main roles. </p>
<p>The concept is presented with the system of solar panels, which leads to the extraction of a large amount of electricity by working of the heat pumps. </p>
<p>About 75% of the kinetic building's facade membrane is provided with stainless steel shutters, which are connected to lighting sensors and automatically open and close according to the sunlight intensity.</p>
<p>The selection of the entire glazing system of the facade is based on sun position and relative U and G parameters of the glazing, proving maximum cooling and heating effect.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Collaboration</span></h4>
<p>The notion of collaboration flows into the layout and planning of each floor of the building.</p>
<p>Each level is conveniently connected via the ramp, along the atrium and provides a comfortable and ample solution for the internal circulation. Bespoke architectural layout fits the bank regulations including the custom-designed furniture is being considered. </p>
<p>One of the key elements of the building design is panoramic (smart) lift systems located in the atrium offering bank employees minimum waiting time and remarkable trip while enjoying atrium space filled with natural daylight and views.</p>
<p>The striking facade of the building is defined by an externally located three two-story atrium spaces revealing to the city an internal content and providing an external connection to the urban texture of the historical neighborhood.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (გიორგი სულიაშვილი(DEV))</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 10:25:43 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Elia Park</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/elia-park</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/elia-park</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/elia/ELIA1.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Belvedere</span></h4>
<p>The center of the park’s projected area, both ideological and functional, is represented by the belvedere, which is a 33 meters high steel structure.</p>
<p>There are two elevators located in the center of the belvedere and the ramp along the structure is aimed for pedestrian visitors to reach the top of the building and enjoy stunning views of Kazbegi.</p>
<p>There is also an ethnic restaurant for 80 people located on the top of the belvedere with panoramic views.</p>
<p>The facade of the structure is finished with metal panels.</p>
<p>The belvedere offers unforgettable views of  Kazbegi to the visitors, allows it to become one of the top landmarks of the region, and attracts lots of tourists and vacationers.</p>
<p>It can become the funicular of Kazbegi.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Functions</span></h4>
<p>The use of the park’s functions is available in all seasons. Building materials, types, and details of structures are specially tailored to Kazbegi's harsh climatic conditions. Of the proposed materials, specially treated stainless steel, processed wood material, natural stone, and concrete finishes should be highlighted.</p>
<p>The project site consists of various functional zones: A children’s playground, a reflecting pond, a restaurant with a terrace, a leisure area, an amphitheater, and a labyrinth.</p>
<p>Proper orientation of the buildings in the park, planning of shades, warming arrangements, and bringing of other energy-saving elements ensure their energy efficiency.</p>
<p>The pond of natural sediments and integrated irrigation system will supplement the optimal use of water resources.</p>
<p>The concept of the park is represented by the minimal interference with the existing landscape and by the systemic situation of new shapes, which gives it special features and meaning.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 10:25:50 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Aragvi Multifunctional Center</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/aragvi-multifunction-center</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/aragvi-multifunction-center</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Aragvi-Multifunctional-Center/ARG-6.jpg" /></p><p>The project concept aims to maximize the positive influence on the environment, rebuild and develop green recreational zones and provides a natural response to the city that lacks green recreational spaces.</p>
<p>From its central location on the Mtkvari Embankment, the site is perfectly placed to capture the unique beauty, historical context and personality of 1500 old capital of Georgia - Tbilisi.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Idea</span></h4>
<p>The idea of ​​the architectural concept is based on the nature of the local landscape, which envisages the seamless connection to the existing environment.</p>
<p>The building configuration, proportion and geometry are defined by the existing context and landscape arrangement. It is also expressed in the formation of an architectural context that is reflected in its forms, textures and colors.</p>
<p>The design volumes mimic the shape of the hills, which are characteristic for the relief and landscape of the area.</p>
<p>The proposed color scheme will seamlessly merge with the surrounding natural landscape and blend into the existing site. Special consideration is given to all existing plantations on-site to ensure that they are preserved and maintained to full extent.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Content</span></h4>
<p>The multifunctional complex consists of 4 major volumes located on 4 story podiums: a hotel, shopping center, office spaces and 2 living quarters.</p>
<p>The Shopping Podium (the unifying podium for the whole complex) - is approximately 40-45 000 sq.m. The building comprises of a semi-open construction of 5 floors, with a mega atrium in the center, which is open to the atmosphere.</p>
<p>The podium fills a large cavity currently formed in the location and repeats and continues the existing contour of the relief.</p>
<p>The project blends in with the landscape providing an intelligent response to the surrounding environment. It merges culturally and historically with the Old City with a new state of the art sophisticated, but yet moderate building composition.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 10:25:15 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Arsha Rest Area</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/leisure-area</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/leisure-area</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Kazbegi-Rest-Area/GOG3.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Idea</span></h4>
<p>The basic idea was to create a strong relationship between the environment and the building. Its shapes, textures materials match the surrounding natural environment and its climate conditions, mountains and rocks what freely blend with a landscape.</p>
<p>Stainless steel panels of warmly colored vertical glazing of brown, bronze, and grey tones give the building an elegant, yet inviting and calm character.</p>
<p>The facade of the building reads as a sequence of roof shapes which repeats the skyline of surrounded mountains.</p>
<p>The ground floor is a unique and open space featuring all the required amenities for state of art modern rest stop: fast food unit, supermarket, pharmacy, local bank branch, children’s entertainment and visitors center.</p>
<p>The second floor is fully occupied by the authentic Georgian restaurant.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Design Approach</span></h4>
<p>The project team succeeded in creating a combination of Georgian tradition and the sophisticated approach of modern architecture.</p>
<p>The historical values have been maintained and brought back to life as well as the responsible use of natural resources and the sustainable approach of the promotion of local businesses.</p>
<p>Arsha Multifunction center will most certainly be a new destination point for visitors from all over the world.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 18:03:22 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gergeti Park</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/gergeti-park</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/gergeti-park</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/gergeti/555555.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Idea</span></h4>
<p>The center of the project site of the park is represented by a spruce tree, which has geometric, ideological and functional significance.</p>
<p>The system of roots joins the center from all sides of the park. It should be noted, that it is a newly planted coniferous plant, which can be decorated for the Christmas and  New Year or be a centerpiece for other events.</p>
<p>There is a small river flowing down the park, with pedestrian bridges arranged.</p>
<p>It creates a natural, pleasant environment and adds a special attractiveness to the area.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Function</span></h4>
<p>The emergence of various activities, the revival of the territory and the gain of previously non-existent multiple functions are the main points of the park design, which is characterized by a variety of entertainment areas: Children’s playgrounds, sports areas, stadium, rope park, run path around the site, bike path and sliding walls of different complexity.</p>
<p>Access to the park is available from various locations and the whole area, as well as buildings, are adapted for people with disabilities.</p>
<p>Different zones are also presented at Gergeti Park, for example, trade zone, picnic zone, camp zone, administration building and cafeteria with open terrace.</p>
<p>The open-air museum (Ethnographic museum with miniature monuments of Kazbegi’s sightseeings) is to be mentioned, which adds special significance to the Gergeti Park.</p>
<p>When designing the project of the park, its sustainability, long-term function and maximum energy efficiency are taken into account.</p>
<p>The use of its features is available in all seasons. The park’s administration has the ability, if needed (seasonally) to assign different functional meanings to the existing zones. For example, in summer, the ice rink transforms into the stage, etc.</p>
<p>Gergeti Park's strict geometric lines, integration of natural cover with architectural shapes and bringing in interesting functions add new traditions and life to the Kazbegi region.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pansheti Recreational Center</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/pansheti-recreational-center</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/pansheti-recreational-center</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Recreational-Space-Near-Pansheti-Village/4.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The pool</span></h4>
<p>The pool and the surrounding area are well-equipped to the highest standards. The project area is arranged for children of different age groups as well as for adults.</p>
<p>The area is represented by recreational spaces that are equipped with photo-voltaic panels, and the synthesis of different variety of them creates an interesting composition at all seasons.</p>
<p>The main pool for adults, featuring a pergola and sunbathing area transforms into the relaxation area in winter, where infrared heaters are installed.</p>
<p>The project area also includes children’s playgrounds with a kid’s pool, multifunctional sports space and administrative building, which is equipped with a first-aid facility, dressing rooms, showers, and public toilets.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Access</span></h4>
<p>Access to the building and movement within the territory is adapted for people with disabilities.</p>
<p>Well organized space, tasting and collecting of drinking water is possible for 12 months for Kazbegi district residents and tourists.</p>
<p>The surrounding areas will be of great interest to the local community in terms of business development.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 10:24:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>OFFICE COMPLEX</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/office-space</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/office-space</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/ABU-DABI/04_evening.jpg" /></p><h4>Concept</h4>
<p>The facade showcases a sense of simplicity and elegance, with crisp edges and smooth surfaces. These clean lines create a visually pleasing and uncluttered appearance. The building architecture embraces the integration of large windows and abundant natural light. Floor-to-ceiling glass panels allow ample daylight to flood the interior spaces, creating a connection between the inside and outside environments. This emphasis on natural light promotes a sense of well-being and enhances the overall work environment.</p>
<p> </p>
<h4>Functions</h4>
<p>We have envisioned open floor plans that maximize flexibility and encourage collaboration. Thus, promoting communication, teamwork, and a sense of community among employees. Here, walls and partitions are minimized, creating expansive and adaptable spaces that can be easily reconfigured to accommodate changing needs. The proposed building design embodies sustainability. Green building practices, energy-efficient systems, and environmentally friendly materials are integrated into the design. Features such as solar panels, rainwater harvesting systems, and efficient HVAC systems contribute to reducing the building’s carbon footprint and promoting a healthier work environment.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mixed-use Development</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/mixed-use-development</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/mixed-use-development</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/chavchavadze-1.jpg" /></p><h5><strong>Functions</strong> </h5>
<p>Behind the building's original and attractive architecture is function and proper planning. The orientation, functional distribution and planning of the building takes into account the needs and interests of the residents. Three independent wings are united by a podium. A garden is planted with different functions.There is a restaurant, a bar and a swimming pool on the roof of the building.  In the yard there are terraced outdoor pools, outdoor bar area and rest area. </p>
<h5><strong>Project architectural planning</strong></h5>
<p>The project is distinguished by its location. Climatic conditions favor landscape planning - a wide variety of species are selected for patios, terraces and rooftop greening. The design of the facade of the hotel is drawn out with a technical and detailed combination. The ratio of interior and exterior design is contrasted with unity, which creates a sense of balance in the overall visual.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 10:25:58 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rain Tower</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/rain-tower</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/rain-tower</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Rain_Tower/10.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Concept</span></h4>
<p>Rain is one of the natural phenomena characteristic of other subtropical cities. There are many hidden or overt messages embedded in the building as a whole, each person will read it differently.  building consists of a base and a tower part. The base of the building is a 6-story rectangular volume, which includes and in  proportion the system merges together with the development. Stylistically, it is a modern building, its proportions and the arrangement of the architectural design of the facade planes are similar to those of a classical building.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Context</span></h4>
<p>The design is artfully balancing very refined, more traditional forms on the lower level that perfectly blends into the given context, while the skyscraper offers sleek, technologically advanced design. The facade of the “Rain Tower” echoes the aesthetics of raindrops and creates a spectacular design to observe. </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Functioin</span></h4>
<p>The tower part of the building 3 volume is divided, the total volume with three-story, narrowed sections visually separates itself. One capacity per function. Every aspect of this development has been meticulously conceived to achieve a delicate balance that pays homage to the classic architecture of old Batumi, while also setting a new standard for the future.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Multifunctional Educational Center</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/multifunctional-educational-center</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/multifunctional-educational-center</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Multifunctional-Educational-Center/GOG11.jpg" /></p><p>The main axis of the project building is represented by a large atrium space, which is a source of natural light and fluidly connects different functions and spaces to each other.</p>
<p>The roof structure of the atrium is created with wooden trusses, which has hexagon-shaped cut-out details on it.</p>
<p>These details create an interesting composition in atrium space by the light of sun rays, which is one of the most important parts of the main concept of the building.      </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Details</span></h4>
<p>Informal learning spaces are extremely popular among STEM students. They meet different needs in promoting collaboration and creating mentoring opportunities between students and faculty.</p>
<p>According to brief some of the spaces are partly isolated, so capsule type, small learning spaces were proposes, located on the second floor and create a private study center. </p>
<p>They are cladded with stainless steel mesh at the side of an atrium in order to have access to the oversized media mesh screen, located on the ground floor, displaying important presentations and a variety of informative news.</p>
<p>Students' library is unique by the wall installation of chemical tubes, whose other side joins the facade, creating an unique part of the exterior.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Context</span></h4>
<p>The details of the existing landscape, location, character and orientation were planned by considering the function and content of the project.</p>
<p>The layout of the Educational Center project and the solar movement trajectory matches with the exploitation schedule of the building and its specifications.</p>
<p>One of the decisive roles in the project's energy efficiency concept is the solar panel system, which leads to the extraction of large amounts of electricity.</p>
<p>To ensure sustainability during the design process, an energy plan was developed, which ensures maximum energy independence of the building.</p>
<p>The project of the Multifunctional Education Center is definitely innovative, modern, and interconnected.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 17:35:58 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Restaurant &quot;Mosavali&quot;</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/restaurant-mosavali</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/restaurant-mosavali</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Doha/4-doha.jpg" /></p><p>Rich wooden decorative panels for ceilings and walls, marble, metal and textile details, which come together to create a distinctive and memorable environment are presented in this exclusive interior. Georgian ornaments with the variety of motives are used on the walls. Decorative partition walls give a special character to the overall design. Curved wooden ceiling with ornaments brings traditional Georgian highlights into the interior, creating special character via artwork of craftsmanship, that creates special ambiance. Arched shapes are used for the bar space to bring in more traditional flavor as they are commonly found in different architectural buildings of various periods in Georgia.</p>
<p>The fundamental design and concept of the project surpass the typical designation of a luxurious restaurant and its main function with the design vision based on the idea of combining the exclusive environment with cultural heritage.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 17:29:17 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>''Kass Land'' Restaurant </title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/restaurant</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/restaurant</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Tsalka/IMG_4937_small.jpg" /></p><p> </p>
<h4>Context</h4>
<p><br />Tsalka Canyon (formerly Dashbashi Canyon) is a deep mountain gorge located 100 kilometers west of Tbilisi in Tsalka Municipality, which provides many options for comfort and adventure in a picturesque setting. While the ceiling reflects the cliffs surrounding the restaurant, the overall aesthetic is simple to let the restaurant's views become the main feature.</p>
<p> </p>
<h4>Details</h4>
<p><br />The color palette and textures are carefully selected based on the context of the environment, taking into account the cues of nature. The restaurant is a cozy environment that offers guests a pleasant and at the same time wonderful environment in one space.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 12:26:18 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Restaurant &quot;Kalaki&quot;</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/restaurant-kalaki</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/restaurant-kalaki</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Restaurant-Kalaki/KAL1.jpg" /></p><p>Its quest was to create a classical and sophisticated environment within the texture of the old town.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Concept</span></h4>
<p>The fundamental design and concept of the project surpass the typical designation of a luxurious restaurant and its main function.</p>
<p>It offers an unparalleled meeting space where people socialize in a magical atmosphere, which lets them escape from hectic city life.</p>
<p>The name of the restaurant – Kalaki, in Georgian means “city.”</p>
<p>The idea of the space is to create a city within a city with a timeless atmosphere that enables visitors to travel through space, in history and culture and interpret the reality in different lenses.</p>
<p>The city inside the city, where time is insignificant, is a place where you can enjoy the magical atmosphere completely distracted from stressful urban routine.</p>
<p>It’s the story told through classic materials, lighting and historical context, which is purposefully imitated in the interior. </p>
<p><em>Sol Omnia Lucet</em> – the Latin caption at the entrance, translates into <em>sun shines for all</em>, it sums up the main idea of the project – creating a restaurant, where everybody finds their own individual space to experience time.</p>
<p>The entire concept of the restaurant and fine dining revolves around the main atrium, the heart of the project, which resembles the typical inner yard of old Tbilisi, residential neighborhoods where inhabitants meet and socialize.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Different Spaces</span></h4>
<p>Different dining halls are connected via the inner courtyard and offer different dining experiences for various settings and functional gatherings.</p>
<p>These planning principles encourage visitors to move around during the evening and explore the space from different perspectives, offering spaces from romantic gateways to casual outdoor seating enables visitors to experience a continuous sense of exploration and excitement at every visit.</p>
<p>A 100-year-old pine right at the entrance of the building was purposefully maintained to enjoy the natural conditions offered by the location. Now this pine adds a green glow to the facade of the restaurant.</p>
<p>The Atrium, artificial sky and outdoor facades used indoors to add a certain theatrical nature to space. Giving visitors the feeling of being part of some performance.</p>
<p>From its food and drinks to the furniture design, this place is designed to awaken feelings.</p>
<p>The Restaurant offers a truly unique experience combining luxurious European settings and styles with local traditions, it creates an unforgettable experience and leaves memories for visitors.</p>
<p>Various stories will be born in such a space, we believe.</p>
<p>We aimed to create a place in which the meaning of the place would be misinterpreted, yet the place would accept various interpretations of visitors.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>THE PLACE – Office Space</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/the-place-office-space</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/the-place-office-space</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Dubai-Office/small_Lobby_3rd_1.jpg" /></p>
<p>By thinking intelligently about the scheme, a positive workplace culture, attracting and retaining talented employees, improving working practices and strengthening brand identity can be achieved. </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Meeting Room</span></h4>
<p>The curved glass meeting room is the signature of this project, which has such benefits as avoiding the monotony of long double-loaded corridors, giving the design an immediately bold and visionary quality. Large openings and plenty of light offer a sense of space and generosity, which becomes the perfect space to work.</p>
<p>Curved shapes combined with minimalist and modern approach demotes clutter and support rational, deliberate design.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wine Cellar</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/wine-shop</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/wine-shop</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Wine-Cellar/new.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Design Approach</span></h4>
<p>The main concept behind of our approach of the wine shop was 8000 winemaking history of Georgian culture and tradition.</p>
<p>The design intention was to highlight the production character of a vineyard and referenced on earthy materials: metal, bricks, wood and clay. </p>
<p>The unique features of the designs are the bespoke details, which are functional as well as aesthetically pleasant and innovative, what has a direct and indirect connection to long-lasting winemaking traditions in Georgia.</p>
<p>An interactive map on the wall, a massive stone table, the wine shelf shaped like the 5th-century Georgian ornament - these are just the part of the interesting features the visitor can discover while walking around the cellar.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Special Details </span></h4>
<p>An interactive map on the wall, a massive stone table, the wine shelf shaped like the 5th-century Georgian ornament - these are just the part of the interesting features the visitor can discover while walking around the cellar.</p>
<p>Each of these details were customized, thoughtfully designed in detail to ensure the unique ambiance and individuality of the wine cellar.</p>
<p>The details separately are interesting to observe, but together create a mesmerizing environment with the capability to reveal our historical heritage to the visitors of the store.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chester's Chophouse &amp; Wine Bar </title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/chester-s-chophouse-wine-bar</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/chester-s-chophouse-wine-bar</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/ka7.jpg" /></p><p>While working on the project, the total area of the restaurant was enlarged, different areas were integrated via moving decorative dividers and was introduced wine degustation area.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Objective</span></h4>
<p>One of the goals of the project was to preserve the existing bar and the decorative wooden panels on the walls, this somehow dictated the direction and selecting on of the color-schemes, materials and textures. </p>
<p>It's noteworthy, that in one of the areas of the restaurant are exhibited Georgian artworks.<br /><br /></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Concept</span></h4>
<p>The restaurant covers different areas - bar, lounge, dining, each with its individual design style, however harmoniously blending in the overall design of the restaurant.</p>
<p>Warm, earthy colors, wooden panels and dividers and other decorative materials are used to create relaxing ambient environment which envisions the local context and function of the project area.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (სოფო კოტრიკაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Restaurant &quot;Aviator&quot; </title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/gudauri-loft-restaurant</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/projects/commercial/gudauri-loft-restaurant</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Cover-GD.jpg" /></p><p>The restaurant belongs to the hotel – "Gudauri Loft", which is located in Georgia’s winter resort – Gudauri.</p>
<p>Project area has increased from 215m2 to 360m2 combining multiple active zones – different sitting areas, show kitchen, bar area, fireplace and a stage. </p>
<p>The project is filled with modern and sophisticated details, that make the space very unique and characteristic to its own name of "Aviator" and location.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Materials</span></h4>
<p>Based on several material relationships – wood, cement, brick and metal, our designers created a completely new space in the region.</p>
<p>With a high ceiling and large, panoramic windows, lots of natural light gets in the interior space.</p>
<p>Open space, dark tones, concrete, leather and solid wood textures create a cozy, comfortable and distinctive environment.</p>
<p>Strict, minimalist and laconic interiors feature functional, vintage furniture.</p>
<p>Handmade metal decorative partitions, concrete columns, a natural stone bar and an original, exclusively made metal fireplace create unforgettable experiences.</p>
<p>The harmonious combination of different architectural solutions is the main concept of this interior.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Commercial</category>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
