<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Spectrum - Hospitality</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:58:02 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (Spectrum Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Hyatt Rustaveli</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/hyatt-rustaveli</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/hyatt-rustaveli</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Hyatt/Front-side.jpg" /></p><p>The historical facade of the build was kept and added 4 story volumes, which seamlessly links with the general architecture of the space.</p>
<p>The added volume carefully responds to the streetscape and urban realm, with strong aesthetics responding to the wider city context. All the ornaments used on the historical facade will be fully restored and maintain an existing aesthetic value.</p>
<p>Stepping into the hotel the visitor is immediately enveloped by a sense of privacy and calm. Every element of the experience has been considered and crafted to exceed the highest expectations.</p>
<p>The design approach has been to make extensive use of natural and classical materials, with contemporary detailing to create a balance of old and new.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Interior</span></h4>
<p>The most interesting feature of the interior design is a partially open atrium, in the center of the first floor, which serves as an inner garden and at the same time as a breakfast area for Hotel guests.</p>
<p>Interior flows seamlessly to the exterior, converting the character into curved forms and uninterrupted sky glazing. The atrium is covered with metal and glass structure, with unique wavy aesthetics.</p>
<p>The innovative use of the roof structure makes the place comfortable to spend time in any weather conditions.</p>
<p>Intelligent planning opens out space and lets the daylight flood in.</p>
<p>Generally, the interior is designed with a classic sophisticated palette of materials executed with the finest contemporary details to blend design and practicality. Contemporary creativity is set against a backdrop of classical riches.</p>
<p>The keynote for the design is contemporary opulence: respect for traditional craftsmanship and high-quality materials, allied with a modern urban sensibility.</p>
<p>The Hotel offers exclusive facilities to its visitors to enjoy the ultimate in five-star luxury living. Hyatt Rustaveli includes a stunning pool with a terrace, gym and other spa facilities, where the guest can relax and get away from the urban routine.</p>
<p>Every aspect of the design is carefully considered to create effortlessly luxurious living spaces that exceed expectations.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:25:21 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Radisson Collection</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/radisson-collection-tsinandali-green-facade</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/radisson-collection-tsinandali-green-facade</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Radisson-Collection-Green-Facade/Radisson-1.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Idea </span></h4>
<p>The idea of having new structure disappear in the historical Chavchavadze garden was generated from the notation of not adding a new element to the garden, but rather creating the extension of the natural environment formed with a new green layer that surrounds the entire structure.</p>
<p>Within the surrounding historical context, the idea of making the new building disappear was conveyed by screening the entire building in a seamless array of natural plantations.</p>
<p>The green facade is the most striking element of the building as it contributes to bringing nature into the resort's landscape. The green facade allows Radisson Hotel to reach far healthier living conditions for both visitors of the hotel and the wider surrounding.</p>
<p>It further reduces energy consumption and protects the building from harsh sunlight during the summer.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:25:09 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NEXT Collection</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/green-cave-multifunctional-complex</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/green-cave-multifunctional-complex</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/next_collection/1v2.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Concept</span></h4>
<p>The goal of the project was to create an organic, multi-functional complex that is binary with the environment. The architecture of the building takes into account the local context and characteristics. Its proportion and geometric forms naturally merge with the system terrain, repeating and emphasizing the contours of the local landscape. Various organic forms, materials and color palette harmoniously blend with the environment.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Context</span></h4>
<p>The project is distinguished by the location. Green Cape is one of the most beautiful seaside resorts in Georgia. Batumi Botanical Garden is one of the most cultivated in Europe. The project are ais distinguished by its proximity to the sea. From the terrace there are breathtaking panoramic views of the sea and the botanical garden. Climatic conditions contribute to landscape planning. A wide variety of species are selected for patio terraces and rooftop gardens.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Functions</span></h4>
<p>Behind the building's original and attractive architecture is function and proper planning. The orientation, functional distribution and planning of the building takes into account the needs and interests of the residents. Three independent wings are united by a podium. A garden is planted with different functions. There is a restaurant, a bar and a swimming pool on the roof of the building.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 10:20:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hotel &quot;Villa Godoly&quot; Facade </title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/villa-godoly-hotel-facade-design</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/villa-godoly-hotel-facade-design</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Facade-Villa-Godoli/14.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Details</span></h4>
<p>The tower of the building is covered with cobblestone, while the horizontal and vertical brick inserts are used as details.</p>
<p>Balconies and arches correspond to the proportions of the historic Kakhetian architecture.</p>
<p>As for the windows, they are very accented and decorated with frames typical for the region.</p>
<p>This facade represents the inspiration and commitment resulted from strong links between ethnicity and modernity, while it's design comes in line with the overall ambiance and designation of the hotel.</p>
<p>By using traditional forms, this beautiful architectural structure becomes intelligible to the people of a particular place as well as for the guests.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Landscape</span></h4>
<p>Special attention was paid to the landscape design. Different varieties of trees were selected, both coniferous and deciduous. 25 X 6 m pool lined with classic elements is fully integrated into the architecture and connects to the hotel building by trails hidden in the green olive bushes.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Local inspiration</span></h4>
<p>As a model of locally-inspired design, which is full of local references and with balconies in antique style, the hotel will set out to shine a light on Kakheti’s rich history and build the region’s profile as an emerging travel hotspot.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 17:39:58 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Apart-Hotel Gonio</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/restaurant2</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/restaurant2</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Gonio/gonio10.jpg" /></p><p> </p>
<h4>Details</h4>
<p>The project is executed in a soothing color scheme combined with accents resonating with the project location, context and seaside theme, also finding a common language with the Client's brand name and the vision.</p>
<p> </p>
<h4>Characteristics</h4>
<p>The hotel reflects the local culture in the interior design, which offers guests a unique and impressive experience. Apart Hotel Gonio is a unique place of rest and relaxation, which is focused on creating a wonderful atmosphere for guests, every detail of which is carefully arranged.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 13:12:16 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Orchard Place</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/residential-complex</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/residential-complex</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Dubai_Tower_Exterior/15-Night.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Landscape</span></h4>
<p>It features a landscaped appearance that was created to achieve an attractive environment and fits in clearly with the city landscape. Part of the landscape includes parks, gardens, private and public spaces, which are an interesting and relaxing place for residents. The ideal concept of landscape design is created by "the journey home" - which residents pass from public spaces to private spaces. </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Function</span></h4>
<p>The multifunctional complex consists of two towers with 25 and 35 shops connected by a 5-story podium. Commercial and office spaces are combined in the building. The project building is ideally suited to the needs of the residents. A part of the terraces, designed with bright and cozy solutions, stands out. The balconies of the living rooms offer spectacular views of the city and are a way for residents to relax.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Radisson Blu</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/radisson-blu</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/radisson-blu</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Rad-Blue/BAR.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Concept</span></h4>
<p>The aim  of project is to create a design that responds to the standards of Radisson Blu and at the same time takes notion of the surrounding context. Interior design of the project is characterized by a combination of classic and modern styles.  All the elements - Shape, light, colour, texture, and pattern come together to create Resort aesthetics. A significant part of the interior design is the terrarium. It  is one of the interesting features adding a special character to the interiors. </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Materials and Textures</span></h4>
<p>Natural and warm materials inspired by coastal aesthetics is used to create a trendy and memorable space. Clean lines, thoughtful use of space and contextual elements are set to deliver meaningful &amp; memorable guest experiences. Each space is infused with stylish elements, coastal inspiration and biophilic touch.<br /> The use of materials and textures let it be different wood, marble, stone, glass and different fabrics all serve one purpose – to harmoniously interact, come in line with Radisson Blu Resort standards and form a very unique, fresh and delightful hotel experience.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 17:29:17 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Canopy by Hilton</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/canopy-by-hilton</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/canopy-by-hilton</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Canopy-1/can-12.jpg" /></p><p> </p>
<h5>Design</h5>
<div>The design methodology takes into consideration the characteristics of different guest types and delivers individual spaces, where each and every guest can Find a Home Away From Home! The welcoming and adaptable public spaces represent a free flow that seamlessly transforms into one another. While considering Canopy standards, each space is infused with contextual elements, neighborhood, cultural inspirations and local art. Carefully selected and designed furniture, accessories, textures and materials make ALL JUST FIT TOGETHER.<br />
<div> </div>
<h5>Character</h5>
<div>The location and surroundings drive design and environmental decisions. The lobby area full of ample sunlight, at night acts as a streetlamp giving out the energy and welcoming atmosphere. Carefully selected color pallets, materials and bespoke furniture create an atmosphere to define a positive stay! A sophisticated palette of natural materials creates a relaxing and soothing atmosphere, articulated by greenish folding doors with eyecatching colorful stained glass accents. The combination of brick, wood, colorful glass, blue velvet and greenish wood is set to create memorable and favorable space for gatherings.</div>
</div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
<div>While most of the architectural elements of the old building are lost, in recognition of its history and to remind visitors that they are in the historical building, the feeling of the old facade was transmitted to the inner side of the facade wall and so that it resembles the old style of the original building. Based on the Latest Architecture of record, tried to find a balance between architectural solutions and material selection for the facade. With the aim to find practical solutions for balconies, roof deck, roof itself, the skylight, and the main entrance, we achieved a very sophisticated and refined appearance.</div>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 21:35:15 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title> The Orchard Place interior</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/residential-complex-2</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/residential-complex-2</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Dubai_Tower_Interior/2-Cop.jpg" /></p><h6><strong>Character</strong></h6>
<p>The materials used in the interior design of the apartments of the project visually echo the exterior of the building. The main detail is the elegant combination of wood and metal. The tone of light colors of the rooms carries the character of the project, which perfectly fits the needs of any resident. The apartments are arranged in such a technical way that the main lighting is the light coming from outside.</p>
<h6><strong>Functionality</strong></h6>
<p>The secret to the amazing quality of the apartments is the attention to detail. The main materials used are marble and walnut parquet, which gives the interior quality and enhances the feeling of coziness. The scale, proportions and hierarchical arrangement of the rooms are harmoniously combined with each other. Kitchens are designed in different layouts that ideally match each room. The lights in the rooms create a sense of coziness and comfort.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 12:50:10 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hampton By Hilton</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/hampton-by-hilton</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/hampton-by-hilton</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/hampton.0/122.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Concept </span></h4>
<p>The aim was to create a design that responds to the standards of Hampton Inn and at the same time takes notion of the surrounding context. The concept supports the notion to deliver quality experience, great value and friendly service as a signature of Hampton brand philosophy.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Design </span></h4>
<p>A modern reception and lobby provides a warm Hamptonality welcome with finishes rooted in the local environment. Welcoming entrance with customizable front desk signage providing a nod to the local area. Soothing tonal combination in line with playful print and colorful accents create fresh and comfortable aesthetics for guests to enjoy. The design leverages the latest design trends, meets the evolving guest needs, and positions the for continuous future relevancy. A palette of honest, natural and warm materials used to create a tranquil and memorable space, the place you want to keep coming back to.clean lines, thoughtful use of space and contextual elements are set to deliver memorable guest stay and quality experience</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 12:50:05 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Radisson Collection</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/radisson-collection</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/radisson-collection</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Sochi-Radisson/launge_5.jpg" /></p><h4> </h4>
<h6><strong>Concept</strong></h6>
<div>The notion of coastal aesthetics of Black Sea Riviera in line with the look &amp; feel of the premium business hotel guide selection of forms, textures and materials. At first glance minimalistic style leaves a special charm, sense of luxury and sophistication to the visitors. Natural materials are extensively used throughout the hotel as a common design language. All materials, fixtures, furniture and accessories are carefully selected to deliver a memorable guest experience.</div>
<h6> </h6>
<h6>Context</h6>
<div>Each space is designed with careful thought for the function, practicality and the sense it should evoke. From the lobby, bar, and restaurant to bedroom suites - planning, shapes, forms, textures and color pallets all support the intention to deliver a proper sense of place; A place where premium lifestyle meets sophistication, areas with authentic local influence supporting the vibrant social scene and memorable experiences. The elegant and adaptable public spaces represent a free flow that seamlessly transforms into one to another. While considering Radisson Collection standards, the layout is offered with the careful thought about the guest’s comfort and their memorable experience. Every piece of furniture, accessories , textures and materials are carefully selected and designed to deliver a premium lifestyle with remarkable sophistication.</div>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hotel &quot;Villa Godoly&quot; Interiors</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/villa-godoly</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/hospitality/villa-godoly</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/vilagodoli/555.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Style</span></h4>
<p>Building materials and styles of the interior were selected according to the rich cultural and historical heritage of the Kakheti region.</p>
<p>Antique Georgian ornaments, furniture details, construction and finishing materials, that characterize this region are used in the interior, which harmoniously meets the standards of the modern hotel.</p>
<p>The hotel interior is enriched with many interesting and functional areas, including a small museum, which is located on the basement floor.</p>
<p>It is presented with exhibits from the different cultural and historical eras of Georgia, that allows guests to get acquainted with the ancient traditions, as well as the cultural works of art.</p>
<p>The walls and columns are lined with Georgian characterizing paver of bricks and stones.</p>
<p>The painting on the wall combines the antiquity of the museum space with the modern style.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Concept</span></h4>
<p>The concept of the reception area represents the analog of the Georgian peasant’s house, and suits the surrounding area with its hospitable design, thus creating cozy and exquisite space.</p>
<p>Traditions of 8000 years of Georgian winery are displayed in the wine cellar, and the tasting room located on the basement floor of the hotel, and offers guests unique hospitality and creates an unforgettable environment.</p>
<p>As for the hotel rooms, the concept of their interiors is driven by the creation of cozy rooms, where guests can feel at Georgian peasant’s house.</p>
<p>The rooms are characterized by the details of the old Georgian furniture, rugs and light-colored walls, which accurately match with modern style and create a unique character.</p>
<p>The hotel "Villa Godoly” project also consists of the lounge, chimney space, restaurant and waiting areas, whose overall appearance is combined with the historical and natural environment, which creates an ideal holiday destination to the visitors.</p>
<p>Ancient culture, tradition, history and exceptional warmth and coziness of the Georgian peasant’s house are united in the concept of this hotel’s project.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Hospitality</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 12:50:05 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
