<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Spectrum - Interiors</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (Spectrum Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Chavchavadze Residence</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/apartment</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/apartment</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/vakos-saxli/chavchavadzesmall.jpg" /></p><p>A large, comfortable sofa acts as a perfect meeting place for visitors and family in this apartment. A pair of matching, modern armchairs offer even more seating against a backdrop of floor-to-ceiling windows. The square coffee table nestles into the nook of the sectional sofa, accessorized with glass tumblers and a coffee table<a title="51 Coffee Table Books to Entertain and Accessorize" href="http://www.home-designing.com/buy-coffee-table-books-for-sale-online"> </a>books. The open floor plan makes the main living space ideal for entertaining. The linear suspension light, that hangs over the island is sleek and modern. </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 11:50:10 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/residential-house-2</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/residential-house-2</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Digomi/Digomi-misagebinew.jpg" /></p><p>Beautiful feature walls including a sophisticated mural, gorgeous nouveau flooring designs that would draw your eyes constantly to your feet, and large examples of eye catching wall art abound. Shut out the summer sun and dive into darkness.</p>
<p>Masculine color scheme with a subtle touch Mood takes priority in the interior. Black-on-black fabrics ensure the textural experience is just as powerful as the visual one.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 12:30:16 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Krtsanisi Apartment</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/private-house-7</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/private-house-7</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Krtsanisi_interior/krts-int1.jpg" /></p><h6><strong>Materials</strong></h6>
<p>The interior and exterior design of the house are harmoniously combined. The color tone of each room is calm and neutral. Wood is used as the main material, which in turn brings warmth to the interior. The main color of the interior is white, which is combined with elements made of modern materials. The material and colors used on the terrace part are matched identically with the design of the house yard.</p>
<h6><strong>Spatial distribution</strong></h6>
<p>The natural textures, light and detail used in each room create a harmonious mood that evokes a sense of balance. Especially noteworthy is the terrace of the house, which carries individualism. The terrace is separated by a glass structure from the central part of the house, from which a panoramic view of Tsavkisi is opened. The spaces of the residential house are decorated with decorative plants.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 18:42:15 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Upper Tskneti Estate</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/upper-tskneti-estates</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/upper-tskneti-estates</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/spectrumprojectimages/homeu.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Interior Concept</span></h4>
<p>The oversized living space comprises sitting, dining, library and bar lounge areas acts as a centerpiece for the entire residence.</p>
<p>It is highlighted with a custom-designed fireplace with distinctive artwork, specially created for the residence.</p>
<p>Created for the cold winter evenings, space provides a place, where a family can just get away from it all and have a time of bonding and togetherness.</p>
<p>The project was designed with a very innovative design style and results in a very unique individual livable space filled with culture, tradition and warm ambiance.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Special Approach</span></h4>
<p>For the special ambiance, the glass roofing features wooden decorative elements, which are custom made and besides the visual apparel they act as a shield from the direct sunlight.</p>
<p>This approach makes the interior more lightweight and at the same time integral part of the existing landscape.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 10:19:11 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/residential-house</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/residential-house</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/australia-tata/Australia_-_2_small_22.jpg" /></p><p>Glossy white marble, gold fixtures, and high-end furniture all come together to experience a sense of enviable luxe into these large living spaces, bedroom designs and chic bathrooms. Grand modern chandeliers create a magical glow in each area, brightly illuminating the bespoke look.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 15:54:37 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ocean View Residence</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/private-estate</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/private-estate</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Australia1/SI1.jpg" /></p>	<p>Architecturally designed multi-level residence with wide sweeping open spaces and grand atrium takes the advantage of natural, raw finishes, spectacular views, function and practicality.</p>
<p>Views are utilized throughout the residence. Functions are distributed in a way to leave the space as a major feature while concentrating on practicality and usability.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Atrium</span></h4>
<p>Preserving the existing tree and bringing nature inside is one of the interesting design elements the house features.</p>
<p>The atrium allows for additional sunlight, while the natural element presents a biophilic approach, highlighting the intention of creating the “Urban Oasis”.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Basement</span></h4>
<p>Basement floor allocates showroom, Board room, office, lounge and wine cellar, in line with Man’s cave and cinema. </p>
<p>The showroom design, allocating 14 cars, is set as an expression of indulgence, passion, power, speed and unmatched extravagance.</p>
<p>With dark tones as the main feature, decorative lighting is set to enhance the qualities of the prized possessions and showcase their audacious curves.</p>
<p>A sense of minimalism surrounding the space complements the forms and allows to better reflect car aesthetics.</p>
<p>The office, edge of lounge and terrace are exposed to mesmerizing caustics that is reflected from the glass flooring of the pool.</p>
<p>This itself will become an interesting feature to observe throughout the day.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Ground Floor</span></h4>
<p>Ground floor allocates living space (living room, library, TV zone, Piano area and kitchen), VIP Guestroom.</p>
<p>Entertainment area (Terrace with pool, Gym, Spa, Sauna, BBQ) and BOH.</p>
<p>The living area creates flowing, airy open space with different arrangements of living area, TV area, library with ladder, dining area and dedicated piano area that can be observed from the living room extending the sweeping view.</p>
<p>Massive terrace overlooking mesmerizing views eliminates line between indoors and outdoors.</p>
<p>With comfortable arrangements of furniture and sunken lounge, it promotes spending maximum time outdoors.</p>
<p>While ideal for family and friend gatherings, the arrangement is comfortable to host large parties and events.<strong> <br /> </strong></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">First Floor</span></h4>
<p>The first floor of the building is divided into two wings.</p>
<p>The Master bedroom suite is located on the North-East side and the Suites are located on North-West of the house.</p>
<p>Both wings are connected via a sky-bridge that creates amazing places where views can be enjoyed.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 13:34:28 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Saguramo Estate</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/saguramo-residence</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/saguramo-residence</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/saguramo/saguramo-railing.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Spaces and Materials</span></h4>
<p>The living room is open and airy, with marble flooring and <span style="color: #333333;">a <a style="color: #333333;" title="45 Beautiful Modern Chandeliers" href="http://www.home-designing.com/buy-modern-chandeliers-for-sale-online">modern chandelier</a> </span>bringing in shape and interest.</p>
<p>The creative gold-toned staircase railing, which separates the living room and bar area from the chimney sitting area, dining room and the kitchen are designed using custom made metal, which elevates this architectural element from something practical to a work of art.</p>
<p>The newels, balusters, and railings of a staircase are making a real design statement and bring a sense of style to space. </p>
<p>L shaped large couch in the living room with two armchairs and a coffee table make the perfect seating arrangement in front of the TV wall. </p>
<p>Modern Onyx wall bar, which is backlit with LED lights to create a warm glow throughout the room is perfect for hosting, while open shelving provides storage and display.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Details</span></h4>
<p>Most of the furniture is custom designed and made to fit the requirements of the family.</p>
<p>This open-concept design creates the perfect layout for social gatherings among friends and family.</p>
<p>The kitchen is relatively simple and straightforward, while stainless steel shelving and tasteful marble countertops merge beauty with functionality.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tkhinvala Private Residence </title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/tkhinvala-private-residence</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/tkhinvala-private-residence</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/tkhinvala/21.jpg" /></p><p>A soft and serene neutral color palette as well as a variety of stones and textures creates a deeply luxurious yet comfortable ambiance.</p>
<p>The living space of an individual house project is tailored to the needs of the modern family with reasonably distributed layout.</p>
<p>The unique color scheme, different natural materials like stone and wood create an elegant and sophisticated space, which is enriched with decorative elements.</p>
<p>One of the most eye-catching design element of this interior is the beautiful bar made of white Alabaster glass, which is illuminated from the inside, creating an unforgettable impression.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 11:48:10 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private Penthouse</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/penthouse-appartments</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/penthouse-appartments</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/spectrumprojectimages/homepp.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Special Design</span></h4>
<p>The main goal of the project was to create a sophisticated and elegant design, for a luxury real estate market.</p>
<p>The design of the penthouse reflects both warmth and classical touch, as well as the desire to create an uncompromising functionality out of every element within the space.</p>
<p>To elegantly exhibit all aspects of classical design, we utilized sophisticated elements and simplified the complex lines by interpreting classical beauty with a modern approach.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Colors</span></h4>
<p>The kitchen and dining rooms are undoubtedly the heart and soul of the entire household.</p>
<p>Designers employed a subtle, contemporary style for these areas, which are structured with a variety of materials in gradations of the blue and green palette that creates a strong sense of dramatic but yet calm feeling.</p>
<p>All furniture was custom designed and made to fit the requirements of the family within all areas of living space.</p>
<p>Interiors of this unique penthouse ultimately culminate in a space, where every member of the family is able to locate preferred space and place for comfort and contemplation.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private Residence</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/private-house-interior-in-tskneti</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/private-house-interior-in-tskneti</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/CknetiInteriorDato/1I.jpg" /></p><p>Upon a first look into the living room, you are instantly struck by the <span style="color: #333333;"><a class="autobesttag" style="color: #333333;" title="See the tag: warm (6 posts)" href="http://www.home-designing.com/tag/warm" rel="nofollow">warm</a></span> wood ceiling and sweeping wide windows. The Colour is calming, furniture is minimal. There is nothing overcomplicated to distract the eye and exhaust the mind yet there is a crisp and confident sense of style, one of complete peaceful self-assurance.</p>
<p>The dining room and living room are wide open with the dominant fireplace coated with a natural stone pattern, creating a timeless design, set to continue having its moment long into the future. </p>
<p>The<span style="background-color: #ffffff;"><span style="color: #000000;"> <span style="color: #333333;"><a style="background-color: #ffffff; color: #333333;" href="http://www.home-designing.com/staircase-design-ideas-inspiration-photos-tips">staircase design</a></span> is </span>op</span>en and light, free of risers to allow the natural daylight and garden view to penetrate from the vast window at its side.  Skylights above the staircase give plenty of sun to both levels of the home.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Bespoke closets meld with wood wall paneling. </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 12:19:11 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tabidze Apartment </title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/tabidze-apartment-interior</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/tabidze-apartment-interior</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Abashidze-Apartment/1-1.jpg" /></p><p>A sophisticated palette of natural shades paints a smooth color story that runs right through from the modern living area and minimalist hallway design, to the decor of three stunning bedrooms and fabulous granite stone covered bathrooms with Onyx details.</p>
<p>In fact, marble is the major player in the main area of the home to really ramp up the level of luxe.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Interior Planning</span></h4>
<p>With the aim to reinterpret traditional design standards, the apartment features the intersection of spaces, surfaces and compositions that are functional and create a bespoke visual effect.</p>
<p>One of the main challenges of the planning process was to create an interior where all of the rooms would have access to the spectacular views of the greenery of "Vake Park" and benefit from ample sunlight.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Natural Materials</span></h4>
<p>White marble, that is present from the entrance to the living room is perfectly balanced with wooden decorative panels on the walls to bring more warmth and class into this minimalistic interior. </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Minimalist spaces</span></h4>
<p>Modern minimalism is present in every single area of this luxury interior, where modern and traditional materials meet to create a bespoke environment, that delivers comfort. </p>
<p>The stylish fireplace in a combination of bookshelves, marble nook and TV is a true eye-catcher bringing in more comfort and tranquility.</p>
<p>The modern sofa that serves as well as a divider between resting and dining areas with its texture and more earthy color balances white marble flooring and walls of the living room.</p>
<p>Kitchen design has to be mentioned with it's minimalist integrated appliances and Corian sink. </p>
<p>The master bedroom features the walk-in wardrobe, that contains a system of walnut shelves and chests of drawers that compliment the tone of the flooring.</p>
<p>Shelf lights highlight the grain and the garments. There is also a private bathroom with an exquisite bathroom design that holds a twin vanity area and a luxury freestanding bathtub.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Paliashvili Residence</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/apartment-interior</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/apartment-interior</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Apartment-Interior-Tbilisi-2020/PAL2.jpg" /></p><p>The landscape of the living room centered around a modern sofa, that captures attention with elegant cobalt upholstery is the most characterizing design approach of this interior.</p>
<p>A color like this can be subtle in other contexts – but in a space dominated by such stark neutrals, it becomes a beacon and anchor for the entire space.</p>
<p>A marble fireplace has also to be mentioned, which adds a classic feel to this unique environment.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Classic and Modern</span></h4>
<p>Classic meets modern in this spectacular dining room, which is part of the living area.</p>
<p>The decorative wall paneling embraces a vintage look with an oversized mirror, which reflects the luxurious chandelier above the dining table. </p>
<p>Adjacent to the living room, you'll find a comfortable kitchen with a sliding door, that accommodates the limited clearance between wall and furniture.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Bedrooms</span></h4>
<p>Bedrooms are designed in a calm, pastel tones embracing a classic, calming and a brilliant atmosphere at the same time. </p>
<p>The upholstered headboards are a great decisions for beds, that are pushed up against the wall, offering a bit more comfort.</p>
<p>The master bedroom design combines classic and comfortable elements, with wooden floor and decorative wall paneling.</p>
<p>It consists of the walk-in closet and a private bathroom with an onyx decorative wall, which once more accents the luxury and unique design of this interior.</p>
<p>One of the most eye-catching design element is the natural marble stone wall (Azul Bahia) in cobalt, presented in the hall, that includes a mirror and a console - the first thing one sees when entering this apartment.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Smart Apartment</span></h4>
<p>Except for the design approaches, this apartment is "smart", combining lighting, heating/cooling, air conditioning and security smart systems.  </p>
<p>A lightweight, refined style used in the design, combined with a variety of materials and color pallets, creates a classic, pleasant and unique environment.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chavchavadze Interior</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/apartment-2</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/interiors/apartment-2</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/chavchavadzewhite/C-111.jpg" /></p><p>Fitted furniture pieces are bespoke, designed to fully utilize the generous room dimensions to their greatest purpose. Atmospheric mood lighting schemes soften the light interior decoration schemes, and accentuate the light tones and interesting design elements, that add texture and depth. Colorful wall art suits the sunny aspect, and brings personality to the neutral palette. Large windows load the interiors with natural sunlight too, along with beautiful views of the city.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interiors</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 12:28:16 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
