<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Spectrum - Residential</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:56:46 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (Spectrum Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Tskneti Dwelling</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/residential-home-2</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/residential-home-2</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Tskneti-Dwelling/abc.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Architectural Solution</span></h4>
<p>The facade is balanced with a classic finish of wood combined with local textured limestone, that gives the house its modernistic, contextual feel.</p>
<p>The oversized terrace encourages the occupants to step outside and enjoy the breathtaking views of Tbilisi.</p>
<p>Innovative roofing technology is used at the terrace of the house, which electronically regulates the slanting angle of the sunlight and at the same time protects the terrace from the rain.</p>
<p>The project includes a stunning infinite pool directly situated on the first level of the yard, facing the beautiful view of nature.</p>
<p>The main feature of the interiors is the natural material palette enriched with the display of the client’s extensive collection of art.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 10:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private Estate</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-estate</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-estate</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Australia1/S1.jpg" /></p><p>Architecturally designed multi-level residence with wide sweeping open spaces and grand atrium takes the advantage of natural, raw finishes, spectacular views, function and practicality.</p>
<p>Views are utilized throughout the residence. Functions are distributed in a way to leave the space as a major feature while concentrating on practicality and usability.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Atrium</span></h4>
<p>Preserving the existing tree and bringing nature inside is one of the interesting design elements the house features.</p>
<p>The atrium allows for additional sunlight, while the natural element presents a biophilic approach, highlighting the intention of creating the “Urban Oasis”.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Basement</span></h4>
<p>Basement floor allocates showroom, Board room, office, lounge and wine cellar, in line with Man’s cave and cinema. </p>
<p>The showroom design, allocating 14 cars, is set as an expression of indulgence, passion, power, speed and unmatched extravagance.</p>
<p>With dark tones as the main feature, decorative lighting is set to enhance the qualities of the prized possessions and showcase their audacious curves.</p>
<p>A sense of minimalism surrounding the space complements the forms and allows to better reflect car aesthetics.</p>
<p>The office, edge of lounge and terrace are exposed to mesmerizing caustics that is reflected from the glass flooring of the pool.</p>
<p>This itself will become an interesting feature to observe throughout the day.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Ground Floor</span></h4>
<p>Ground floor allocates living space (living room, library, TV zone, Piano area and kitchen), VIP Guestroom.</p>
<p>Entertainment area (Terrace with pool, Gym, Spa, Sauna, BBQ) and BOH.</p>
<p>The living area creates flowing, airy open space with different arrangements of living area, TV area, library with ladder, dining area and dedicated piano area that can be observed from the living room extending the sweeping view.</p>
<p>Massive terrace overlooking mesmerizing views eliminates line between indoors and outdoors.</p>
<p>With comfortable arrangements of furniture and sunken lounge, it promotes spending maximum time outdoors.</p>
<p>While ideal for family and friend gatherings, the arrangement is comfortable to host large parties and events.<strong> <br /> </strong></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">First Floor</span></h4>
<p>The first floor of the building is divided into two wings.</p>
<p>The Master bedroom suite is located on the North-East side and the Suites are located on North-West of the house.</p>
<p>Both wings are connected via a sky-bridge that creates amazing places where views can be enjoyed.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 18:30:02 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-tskneti</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-tskneti</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/ckneti/4.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Special Detail</span></h4>
<p>To prevent cutting down the trees, an interesting detail of the project was developed, such as cut out slabs of terraces and roof, where existing pine trees were pinched.</p>
<p>This idea makes building and nature an integral part of each other.</p>
<p>The project facade is lined with high-quality wood material and travertine tiles, that further promotes border-free integration of architecture with the surrounding landscape.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Integration</span></h4>
<p>The project of the house outlines the synthesis between nature and interior in keeping with a trend of comfort and domesticity.</p>
<p>The relationship between the room and the external landscape is especially evident with the large living-room glass wall with opening, which is located on the ground floor and connects to the terrace framing a view of the pinewood landscape.</p>
<p>Apart from the living room, the kitchen and the cabinet spaces are conveniently connected to the yard.</p>
<p>The reflective pool, located along the terrace, in front of the living room, emphasizes the aesthetics of the harmonious fusion of nature and living spaces.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Energy Efficiency</span></h4>
<p>During the design process of the project, special attention was paid to the correct orientation of the building, warming and selection of the right materials to achieve maximum energy efficiency.</p>
<p>The project of a private house in Tskneti represents the ideal synthesis of the natural pinewood landscape and the building.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 13:00:38 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PRIVATE PENTHOUSE</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-penthouse</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-penthouse</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Penthouse-Anano/LIVING_ROOM_2.jpg" /></p><h4>Context</h4>
<p>Nestled in the heart of Batumi, on the shores of the Black Sea, our exceptional penthouse offers a truly remarkable living experience. Batumi, a jewel of Georgia's coastline, is renowned for its vibrant culture, stunning natural beauty, and a burgeoning reputation as a cosmopolitan destination. This penthouse is perfectly situated to allow you to immerse yourself in the city's unique blend of old-world charm and modern allure. Perched atop an architectural masterpiece, the penthouse provides awe-inspiring views and a sense of grandeur.</p>
<p> </p>
<h4>Details</h4>
<p>As you step into this penthouse, you'll be transported into a realm of lavishness and sophistication. With every detail meticulously crafted, it offers a lifestyle like no other. The penthouse is perched atop an architectural marvel, allowing you to bask in breathtaking panoramic views of both the cityscape and the serene Black Sea. Inside, a harmonious blend of modern aesthetics and timeless elegance awaits. High-end finishes, bespoke furnishings, and carefully curated décor create an ambiance of refined opulence. The open-plan living spaces are designed to maximize natural light and the sense of space, while the chef's kitchen is a culinary enthusiast's dream. The penthouse is not just a home; it's an invitation to savor life at its finest.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 10:22:50 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NEXT Address</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/next-address</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/next-address</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/NEXT-ADRESS/N001.jpg" /></p><p>The building's elegant and innovative design, along with its unconventional aesthetics, will seamlessly blend with the traditional elements and distinctive features of Batumi's old and new architecture, creating a harmonious and balanced environment. <br /> Adding to the allure of the complex, panoramic elevators provide breathtaking views of Batumi and the sparkling sea. Towering at a height of 206 meters, the building houses luxurious penthouses on its top floor, offering an elevated living experience with unparalleled vistas. </p>
<h4><strong>The Podium</strong></h4>
<p><br /> The architectural structure of the complex is divided into two main parts: a vibrant green podium housing commercial facilities and three multi-story residential complexes. The podium features a refreshing green terrace and a captivating swimming pool, offering residents a serene oasis within the bustling city. One of the most remarkable and distinguishing aspects of the building is its green facade. Enveloped entirely by a natural covering, the podium bears both visual appeal and ecological significance. The green facade efficiently absorbs a substantial amount of CO2, reduces energy consumption, and contributes to a healthier environment. The diverse range of plant species used in its creation fosters biodiversity and promotes environmental well-being.</p>
<h4><strong>Striking Features</strong></h4>
<p>In addition to its captivating location and luxurious amenities,  Next Address boasts several striking features that set it apart. The sleek and modern architecture, characterized by its clean lines and geometric shapes, is a testament to contemporary design principles. The innovative façade design further enhances the building's visual appeal, making it a true architectural marvel in Batumi.</p>
<p>The carefully crafted façade not only adds to the building's aesthetic charm but also serves functional purposes. It incorporates energy-efficient elements, contributing to the complex's sustainability goals and reducing the overall environmental impact.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the architectural design of the complex ensures seamless integration with the surrounding environment. Residents of the "Next Address" complex can truly enjoy the best of both worlds - a visually stunning architectural masterpiece and a comfortable, modern living space that caters to their every need.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 17:33:43 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-in-tskneti-2</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-in-tskneti-2</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Tskneti-Giovanni/s1.jpg" /></p><p>The project of the house outlines the synthesis between nature and the interior in keeping with a trend of comfort and domesticity.</p>
<p>The relationship between the room and the external landscape is especially evident with the large living-room glass wall with an opening, which is located on the ground floor and connects to the terrace framing a view of the pinewood landscape.</p>
<p>Apart from the living room, the kitchen and the cabinet spaces are conveniently connected to the yard.</p>
<p>The reflective pool, located along the terrace, in front of the living room, emphasizes the aesthetics of the harmonious fusion of nature and living spaces.</p>
<p>During the design process of the project, special attention was paid to the correct orientation of the building, warming and selection of the right materials to achieve maximum energy efficiency.</p>
<p>The project of a private house in Tskneti represents the ideal synthesis of the natural pinewood landscape and the building.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 17:31:30 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House </title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-3</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-3</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/H190/S190www-Recovered.jpg" /></p><p>The large, stained glass windows and open staircase provide maximum inflow of natural light into the interior and at the same time allow to enjoy the views of Lisi Lake.</p>
<p>Wide terraces are designed to make staying on fresh air more comfortable.</p>
<p>Strict, straight lines and geometrical shapes of the architecture create a modern ambiance, that in combination with natural decorative materials sets the ground for cozy, comfortable living.</p>
<p>The house takes advantage of the basement where are distributed different functions. </p>
<p>The project is energy efficient, incorporates the principles of a healthy home, and blends harmoniously with nature.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 14:57:10 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PRIVATE HOUSE</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-8</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-8</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/LG-renders/LISI_LG_2.jpg" /></p><h4>Materials</h4>
<p>The main material of an individual private house is wood, which is perfectly suited to the local environment. The details presented in the exterior of the house create a feeling of warmth and sophistication.</p>
<p> </p>
<h4> Details</h4>
<p>The residential house is distinguished by the design of the yard, where the living spaces are located. The pool located in the yard of the residential house is distinctive, which creates an excellent atmosphere for gatherings and gives individuality to the exterior of the house. The spaces are decorated with plants and many decorative elements that fit perfectly into the surrounding environment.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:30:02 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PRIVATE HOUSE</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-7</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-7</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/2-renders/black12.jpg" /></p><h4>Materials</h4>
<p>The main material of an individual private house is wood, which is perfectly suited to the local environment. The details presented in the exterior of the house create a feeling of warmth and sophistication.</p>
<p> </p>
<h4> Details</h4>
<p>The residential house is distinguished by the design of the yard, where the living spaces are located. The pool located in the yard of the residential house is distinctive, which creates an excellent atmosphere for gatherings and gives individuality to the exterior of the house. The spaces are decorated with plants and many decorative elements that fit perfectly into the surrounding environment.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 18:30:02 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House </title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-4</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-4</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/ananossaxli2/1-patara.jpg" /></p><p>Minimalistic modern lines of the house are mitigated by the warmth of natural materials in the finishes of – natural stone, wood, steel, and textured plaster.</p>
<p>Those floor-to-ceiling windows that let in so much light allow nature to make its way in.</p>
<p>Landscaping is used to soften the hard lines of the exterior.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Layout</span></h4>
<p>The house has an individual layout with a beautiful staircase space, connecting the first floor with living room, dining room, kitchen, and 2 bedrooms, and the basement floor with one bedroom, bathroom, children’s room, and a cabinet, from which there is an exit in the garden with the pool and a gazebo.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Roofline</span></h4>
<p>Roofline plays a big role in the architectural design of this house project, while it tends to use modern, flat roofing, that connects with the terrace at the main entrance. </p>
<p>The flat roof is an element that contrasts with the topography, offering the house stability, allowing it to stand out.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 15:25:48 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-5</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-5</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Saguramo-House/sag000.jpg" /></p><p>The project of the house outlines the synthesis between nature and the interior in keeping with a trend of comfort and domesticity.</p>
<p>The relationship between the room and the external landscape is especially evident with the large living-room glass wall with an opening, which is located on the ground floor and connects to the terrace framing a view of the pinewood landscape.</p>
<p>Apart from the living room, the kitchen and the cabinet spaces are conveniently connected to the yard.</p>
<p>The reflective pool, located along the terrace, in front of the living room, emphasizes the aesthetics of the harmonious fusion of nature and living spaces.</p>
<p>During the design process of the project, special attention was paid to the correct orientation of the building, warming and selection of the right materials to achieve maximum energy efficiency.</p>
<p>The project of a private house in Saguramo represents the ideal synthesis of the natural pinewood landscape and the building.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 18:30:02 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-6</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-6</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Mika_Lisi_House/MIKA-3.jpg" /></p><h5><strong>Concept</strong></h5>
<p>The project’s concept brings elegance through simplicity as the exterior blends sleek lines with a neutral color palette. The plan has evolved through a series of functions after carefully considering the functionality and practicality of the villa. The project’s spaces were designed by changing the development strategy accordingly which enabled the creation of diverse spaces as per the user’s specific desires. The project’s design has been characterized by three distinct volumes, where one volume is cantilevered diagonally on the top which adds extra complexity to the structure. These masses are placed to create a unified look that is further spatially connected.</p>
<h5><strong>Features</strong></h5>
<p>The exterior is made of vertical divisions of dark grey concrete that contrast smoothly with the tight rhythm of the timber cladding, which bring in warmth and sophistication. In addition, large glass windows are incorporated that beautifully overlook the Lake where natural light floods in. The solid surface cladding used brings a sense of privacy and safety to the house and also establishes interesting solid-void (light and shadow) encounters with daylight. Moreover, a metallic art sculpture has been installed over a tranquil waterbody that creates a captivating focal point on the villa front, facing the street.</p>
<h5><strong>The Facade</strong></h5>
<p>The façade has been designed using alphabets and symbols from the Georgian language to bring in a connection to the cultural context of the region as well as create a sense of unique identity. The characters were placed in such a way that it creates a sense of rhythm and progression across the exterior. These metal perforated screens also visually obstruct the enclosed spaces toward the neighborhood. During the day, natural light rays enter into the house through the perforations and give rise to an interesting play of shadows; while artificial lighting pierces out during the night and hence makes the façade change dynamically during different times of the day.         </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 10:25:46 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-2</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-2</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Marat-Lisi_House/5.jpg" /></p><h5><strong>Design </strong></h5>
<p>The villa exterior is composed of vertically striped concrete cladding along with the presence of wooden louvers that not only control the amount of light entering the interior spaces, but also provide privacy to the occupants. The grey and brown color palette blends the project cohesively with the context and evokes a purist mentality. The floor-length glazing adds a modern touch along with providing magnificent views of the landscape. This transparency also lets the user experience the changes in weather, sun, and seasons from the internal spaces. The gabled roof is cladded with darker tiles than the concrete exterior, which also gives the viewer a sense of hierarchy on seeing the building. To top this off, a bright red metal sculpture is placed on a still and shallow water feature on the front which brings in a pop of color and exciting central viewpoint.</p>
<h5><strong>Features</strong></h5>
<p>The villa is surrounded by thick landscaping that is carefully planned to add an extra layer of tranquility that gives a soothing and Zen-like effect. Also, the use of these plants not only enhance the visual appeal but also give a scented breeze from the flora as the winds flow through them. On the upper floor, a spacious living area opens up to a stunning infinity-like swimming pool with a glass wall on one face, providing unobstructed water views to users on the ground floor. This creates an effect that makes the pool appear as though it is floating in the air. The pool area that overlooks the greenery below, creates a serene oasis that is perfect to unwind after work or relax on weekends. Moreover, the villa features tapered windows on one of its elevations, to angle the window in such a direction that it opens the room to the optimal view of the surroundings.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 18:30:02 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/Vako_Tsavkisi_House/vak-1.jpg" /></p><h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Details</span></h4>
<p>An individual private house evokes a sense of coziness and balance. Large windows allow sunlight to enter, which makes the house appear brighter and cozier. The wide and open terraces present in the house create an ideal atmosphere for gatherings and relaxation.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Material</span></h4>
<p>The main materials used are concrete, wood and metal. Their combination creates an elegant and individual character. A distinctive feature is the terrace of the house, which is surrounded by a glass railing, which creates a sense of space. The lights on the walls of the residential house emphasize the unique and individual character. The design of the residential house is distinguished by the abundance of open spaces, which are a means of relaxation. The organic forms, materials and color gamut used in the exterior design blend harmoniously with the environment.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:30:02 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wood Cabin</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/wood-cabin</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/wood-cabin</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Wood-cabin-NY/smallcottage.jpg" /></p><p>The wooden cottage was designed with the intention to connect the project with nature, take advantage of the back yard views and create a cozy atmosphere for the owners to escape urban hectic environment.<br />The contrast between the wild nature and a safe, cozy interior space is emphasized throughout, strongly guiding the overall experience. Simplicity, natural materials and minimalism are utilized to deliver peace and harmony. The overall experience is to offer owners a feeling of detachment from the outside world.<br />Straight lines, modern architectural elements in combination with natural materials and minimalistic approach to not exhaust the eye, creates unique and tranquil atmosphere. <br />The glass curtain wall while bringing ample sunlight into the interior and presenting mesmerzing views, at the same time erases line between the interior and exterior.<br />The house was designed with attention to energy-efficiency and incorporates healthy home standards.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 17:39:58 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biophilic House </title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/biophilic-house</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/biophilic-house</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/nushebi/S2.jpg" /></p>	<p>Set in Nature the project rethinks our innate biological connection with nature. Considering different patterns of Biophilic design creates an urban retreat for the residents.</p>
<p>We have challenged ourselves to create a private sanctuary that would connect to nature and let it become part of the residence. </p>
<p>From visual &amp; non-visual connection to nature, thermal variability, presence of water, dynamic &amp; diffuse light, connection to the natural system, material connection to nature, biomorphic forms and patterns to complexity and order the design incorporates different patterns of biophilic design to achieve maximum comfort for residents, for their harmony and well-being.</p>
<p>Natural materials are used throughout the design, both the façade and interior.</p>
<p>Wooden texture brings toothing warmth to the private house that is enriched with natural stone and mesh covered with greenery. <br /> <br />The Winter garden is one of the main features of the house.</p>
<p>It is located on the second floor. Each room surrounding it takes advantage of the amazing green garden view.</p>
<p>The garden serves as an oasis throughout the winter when using terraces and outdoor spaces are less actual.  <br /> <br /> The house is allocated in a way to take maximum advantage of outdoor space and create an amazing stop to spend sphere time on fresh air.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 17:08:41 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House </title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-residential-house-lisi-hills</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-residential-house-lisi-hills</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/bokahouse/4-pataraaaaaaaaaaaaaaa.jpg" /></p><p>The stairs arranged on the slope lead to the main floor entrance, where the living room, dining room, kitchen, cabinet, storage, guest bedroom and bathrooms are located.</p>
<p>The second-floor design acknowledges both the importance of outdoor spaces and privacy by giving each bedroom its own separate balcony and allowing residents to retreat to their own corner or commune in the lounge area, which has a beautiful view of the patio.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Patio</span></h4>
<p>One of the most important details of this residential house project is the 50 sq. m patio, which is arranged on the South-East part of the house.</p>
<p>A captivating patio design provides a modern home with a special sense of serenity and allows nature to become a major part of a home’s makeup.</p>
<p>Enclosed garden spaces act as personalized nature retreats that feed into adjacent interior spaces via the blurred boundaries of glass walls.</p>
<p>The roof of the patio is made of steel structure and glass, providing constant sunlight and protection from the rain.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">The Facade</span></h4>
<p>The facade is balanced with glass combined with stainless steel panels, which gives the house its modernistic, contextual feel.</p>
<p>Stainless steel panels change color according to climatic conditions, which makes the facade look different at different times.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 13:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Private House </title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-in-tskneti</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/projects/residential/private-house-in-tskneti</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Projects/tskneti-pat/1.jpg" /></p><p>Set into sloping terrain, the house is arranged over a double level, with the front yard deepening as it steps down the hill.</p>
<p>The facade is balanced with a classic finish of wood combined with local textured limestone, which gives the house its modernistic, contextual feel.</p>
<p>The oversized terrace encourages the occupants to step outside and enjoy the breathtaking views of Tbilisi.</p>
<p>The Minimalist aesthetics radiate a warm, earthy and traditional essence that creates a soothing sight to behold.</p>
<p>The sliding glass doors and oversized windows let in the ample sunlight while connecting the interior with the outer surrounding.</p>
<p>Designing a swimming pool in a way it is connected to the residence and has an endless edge gives the entire setting a truly magical feeling and creates the perfect atmosphere to relax.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Residential</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 13:00:38 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
