<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Mugo - Stories</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://mugo.ge/stories</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:56:33 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://mugo.ge/stories?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (Mugo Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Enhancing Interior Spaces with Wood: A Timeless Design Element</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/enhancing-interior-spaces-with-wood-a-timeless-design-element</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/enhancing-interior-spaces-with-wood-a-timeless-design-element</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/woodi-in-interior/e21bcae77a93f4c6c82605aab1b7c913.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>Natural beauty and warmth</strong>: Wood adds a sense of warmth, comfort, and a connection to nature within interior spaces. Its natural grains, textures, and unique patterns create an inviting and cozy ambiance that can't be replicated by synthetic materials.</p>
<p><strong>Versatility:</strong> Wood comes in a wide range of species, colors, and finishes, making it highly versatile in interior design. It can be used for flooring, wall paneling, ceilings, furniture, cabinetry, and even decorative accents, offering endless possibilities for design and customization.</p>
<p><strong>Timeless appeal:</strong> Wood has been used in architecture and interior design for centuries, and its timeless appeal ensures that it never goes out of style. It can complement both traditional and contemporary designs, making it suitable for a wide range of interior styles.</p>
<p><strong>Durability and longevity:</strong> High-quality wood is durable and can withstand wear and tear, making it a long-lasting material for interior applications. Properly cared for, wood can retain its beauty and structural integrity for many years, adding value to the overall design.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/woodi-in-interior/2d3850fece76f1d6b235c13771df8b39.jpg" alt="" width="478" height="478" /></p>
<p> <strong>Acoustic properties:</strong> Wood has excellent acoustic properties, which can help reduce noise and echo in indoor spaces. This makes it an ideal material for flooring and wall paneling in areas where noise control is essential, such as offices, libraries, or music rooms.</p>
<p><strong>Environmental sustainability:</strong> As a renewable resource, wood can be responsibly harvested and replanted, making it a sustainable choice for interior design. When sourced from well-managed forests, using wood can contribute to a more eco-friendly and environmentally conscious design approach</p>
<p><strong>Connection to cultural heritage:</strong> In many cultures, wood holds significant cultural and historical importance. Incorporating wood into interior design can evoke a sense of tradition and connection to cultural roots, adding depth and meaning to the space. </p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/woodi-in-interior/000001.jpg" alt="" width="472" height="652" /></p>
<p><strong>Easy to work with:</strong> Wood is relatively easy to work with compared to other materials, allowing for various design possibilities. It can be carved, shaped, and joined to create intricate and artistic designs, making it a favorite material for skilled craftsmen and artisans.</p>
<p><strong>Biophilic design benefits:</strong> Biophilic design is an approach that seeks to connect people with nature in the built environment. The use of wood in interior design supports this concept, promoting well-being, reducing stress, and enhancing productivity by bringing natural elements into indoor spaces.</p>
<p>Overall, wood's importance in interior design lies in its ability to add beauty, character, and sustainability to spaces while creating a welcoming and harmonious environment for occupants.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Stories</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 13:26:02 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Importance of Natural Light in Interior Design</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/the-importance-of-natural-light-in-interior-design</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/the-importance-of-natural-light-in-interior-design</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/For-story/c892e5343d60eaba873f88136f15706b.jpg" /></p><p> </p>

<p><strong>Enhances Aesthetics</strong>: Natural light brings out the true colors and textures of the elements in a space, making the interior design look more vibrant and appealing. It can highlight architectural features, artwork, and furnishings, creating a visually pleasing atmosphere.</p>
<p><strong>Mood and Well-Being</strong>: Exposure to natural light has a positive impact on human psychology and well-being. Sunlight stimulates the production of serotonin, which contributes to a person's happiness and overall mood. As a result, spaces with abundant natural light tend to feel more inviting, uplifting, and comfortable.</p>
<p><strong>Visual Comfort and Task Performance:</strong> Proper natural lighting reduces eye strain and discomfort, making it easier to perform various tasks, such as reading, working, or cooking. It also helps to reduce the reliance on artificial lighting during the day, which can lead to energy savings</p>
<p><strong>Spatial Perception:</strong> Natural light creates a sense of openness and spaciousness in a room. Rooms that are well-lit with natural light appear larger and more welcoming than poorly lit spaces, which can feel cramped and claustrophobic.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/For-story/e76e240ae2a4e20492f596dc54a94873.jpg" alt="" width="389" height="410" /></p>
<p><strong>Connection to the Outdoors</strong>: Incorporating natural light into interior design connects the indoor space with the outside world. It allows occupants to feel more in tune with nature and the changing outdoor environment, providing a sense of harmony and tranquility.</p>
<p><strong>Sustainability and Energy Efficiency</strong>: By maximizing the use of natural light during the day, artificial lighting requirements can be reduced, leading to lower energy consumption and decreased utility costs. This aligns with sustainable design principles and environmentally conscious practices.</p>
<p><strong>Flexibility and Adaptability:</strong> The intensity and direction of natural light change throughout the day and across seasons. This dynamic lighting quality allows interior spaces to adapt to different moods, functions, and activities, providing a dynamic and ever-changing ambiance</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/For-story/bf4ce9b3f9a1a55d11accb0711ea24ce.jpg" alt="" width="384" height="577" /></p>
<p><strong>Health Benefits</strong>: Exposure to natural light is associated with various health benefits, including better sleep patterns, improved Vitamin D synthesis, and increased circadian rhythm regulation. Incorporating natural light into interior design can contribute to occupants' overall health and well-being.</p>
<p>To make the most of natural lighting in interior design, it's essential to consider factors such as building orientation, window placement, the use of reflective surfaces, and the selection of window treatments that allow for light control when needed. With a well-thought-out design approach, natural lighting can significantly improve the overall quality and appeal of an interior space.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (Confidential)</author>
			<category>Stories</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 17:22:32 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Home Decor Trends 2021 - A Comfortable Home</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/home-decor-trends-2021-a-comfortable-home</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/home-decor-trends-2021-a-comfortable-home</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/2021trends/InteriorTrends2021_Mixitup-TheNordroom.jpg" /></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">A Comfortable Home</span></h4>
<p>Comfort is the most important "home decor trend" at the moment, it is probably what we’re all longing for. We’ve been spending more time at home than ever before, not just for relaxing but we’ve also started working at home.</p>
<p>Big comfy sofas in comfortable fabrics (velvet is still a big design trend) are something that we’ll see a lot in the future and this new seating is often in bright colors like pink, mustard yellow and green.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/2021trends/1fc5f231-c31e-422f-a4ea-d1fa4bf764e9_rw_1920.jpg" alt="" width="1172" height="880" /></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">A Natural Look At Home</span></h4>
<p>We've all been feeling a stronger connection to nature in the last year. Light-filled rooms with plants are gaining popularity.</p>
<p>Decorate your home with greenery, use window sills to grow herbs and add flower boxes to add a little to your home.</p>
<p>Also our furniture and home decor can add to that natural look with items made of natural materials such as wicker and rattan<i>.</i></p>
<p>Natural elements such as terracotta vases, marble coffee tables, wicker baskets, and wooden furniture, all work together to add texture and warmth to a room, creating a more organic look that can produce a relaxed, calming vibe.</p>
<p>So we’re not only seeing green colors and natural materials in home decor but also more focus on sustainability.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/2021trends/InteriorTrends2021_Mixitup-TheNordroom.jpg" alt="" width="1170" height="836" /></p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interior Design</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 13:38:10 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Must-Know Tips for Building an Energy-Efficient Home</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/architecture/must-know-tips-for-building-an-energy-efficient-home</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/architecture/must-know-tips-for-building-an-energy-efficient-home</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/ENERGYSAVINGDEVICES/energy-effiecint-house.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>All About Location</strong></p>
<p>While building an <strong>energy-efficient home</strong>, location, shape, and construction materials are prime considerations that will significantly influence the heating and cooling requirements. The maximum use of passive solar energy gain in winters and reduction of the heat gain during summers is the ideal scenario. It is achieved by optimizing the location, orientation, and landscaping of the home.</p>
<p>Home orientation determines how much sun your house will be getting.  This has a direct impact on your home’s temperature.</p>
<p>Design the home to take advantage of different sun angles. The midday sun is at a low angle in winter and a high angle in summer. Based on this, position your home to reduce heating and cooling expenses<strong>. </strong>Homes situated on the south side of the street-facing north get a lot of sunlight at the back of the house. Homes on the north side get shade during the summer afternoons in their backyards.  Similarly, if you’re living in a colder climate, you’d want to choose your windows’ location to be able to absorb maximum sunlight. South-facing homes capture sunlight in the winter while blocking it during summer.</p>
<p><strong>Ventilation Systems</strong></p>
<p>A well-designed ventilation system for an energy-efficient house doesn’t only provide comfort but also helps in energy saving by preventing the overuse of electrical appliances used for heating and cooling purposes. Moreover, <a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/blog/home-ventilation/">home ventilation</a> also filters out contaminated air. The simplest form of ventilation systems are windows and mechanical systems with fans used to keep the interior pleasant. Your home design should ensure healthy and natural ventilation.</p>
<p>The ventilation system is an integral part of your energy-efficient house design because it moves air and moisture across the building envelope’s barrier, and sometimes it also moves heat. A well-thought-out ventilation system can significantly minimize your overall energy usage and help make your home more energy-efficient.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/ENERGYSAVINGDEVICES/energy-effiecint-house.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><strong>Energy Saving Devices</strong></p>
<p>With the progress and advancement in technology, the selection of relevant smart devices can help you in <a href="https://paylesspower.com/blog/energy-saving-tips/">saving and optimizing your home energy</a>. Such devices use minimum energy to function as compared to regular appliances, thus further reducing your electricity bills. An energy-efficient home needs to be smart to give a good return on investment and save money in the longer run.</p>
<p>You can utilize <a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/">smart AC controllers</a>, smart thermostats, smart bulbs, smart blinds, kitchen appliances, etc., to equip your smart home. Taking the example of smart AC controllers, they function by regulating your air conditioner usage according to your usage habits throughout the day helping you save 25% on your cooling and heating bills. They can also be coupled with other <a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/blog/10-best-smart-home-climate-control-appliances/">smart home climate control appliances</a> connected with Alexa or Google Home for further benefits.</p>
<p><strong>Design for Water Conservation</strong></p>
<p>An increasing number of energy-efficient houses are incorporating water-saving systems. For instance, homeowners are going for <a href="https://www.choice.com.au/home-improvement/water/saving-water/articles/guide-to-greywater-systems">greywater recycling systems</a>. Greywater is the waste water from showers, sinks, laundry tubs, and washing machines. You can have a diversion system installed that carries the greywater from your washing machine to your bathroom or your garden.</p>
<p>This system can <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2014/jul/21/greywater-systems-can-they-really-reduce-your-bills">decrease your water usage by about 50%</a>, helping reduce your water bills.</p>
<p>Moreover, you can also save water during the shower and washing dishes by incorporating new technology in your house. New low-flow water fixtures in the kitchen and showers reduce the amount of water coming out of them but distribute it more evenly.</p>
<p><strong>Roofing Materials</strong></p>
<p>The roofing material is another important consideration when building an energy-efficient home. The material used for the roof of your house can absorb less heat by deflecting the sunlight, thus maintaining a constant temperature of your home. The choice of roofing materials makes a difference in overall energy efficiency. The materials used to build the roof help you with energy conservation, decrease air pollution and greenhouse gas emissions, and keep your home cool without air conditioning.</p>
<p>Initially, the selection of a roof could be expensive, but in the long run, it pays back and reduces your bill by regulating the temperature of your home during summers.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Go Solar</strong></p>
<p>Solar Panels can help build energy-efficient homes. If your area is exposed to the sun throughout the year, then solar panels will surely reduce your electricity bills. These panels don’t require extensive maintenance, so it’s a one-time investment that saves you from a lot of hassle and makes you self-sufficient.</p>
<p>Solar panels are an environmentally friendly option since solar energy is converted into electrical energy, reducing harmful greenhouse gases that contribute to global warming. Once you have installed solar panels, you can use the energy for a host of different uses, such as a solar heater for heating water, bulbs, and practically any home appliance.</p>
<p> <img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/ENERGYSAVINGDEVICES/solar-panels.jpg" alt="" width="892" height="502" /></p>
<p> </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 16:02:12 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Small Apartment Decorating Ideas &amp; Tips: How to Design Small Spaces</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/small-apartment-decorating-ideas-tips-how-to-design-small-spaces</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/small-apartment-decorating-ideas-tips-how-to-design-small-spaces</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/smallapartment/small-dining-space.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>A light color palette</strong></p>
<p>It’s always a challenge to approach your interior design’s color scheme in a holistic fashion. However, when it comes to small apartment design, your color palette should help you create an illusion of a bigger space. Generally, you should consider light colors such as white, off-whites, pastels, or muted colors for your apartment. These colors help create an open and expansive feeling.</p>
<p>Pastel colors are colors that belong to the milky and desaturated family. These are colors that have enough white mixed in to offer a colorful yet soft look.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/smallapartment/pastel_1.jpg" alt="" width="837" height="414" /></p>
<p><strong>Tiny Apartment Layout Dos and Don’ts</strong></p>
<p>Laying out furniture in a tiny dorm or apartment can make or break the space because furniture often consume substantial space. Here are a few dos and don’ts when planning your furniture layout:</p>
<p><strong>Dos:</strong></p>
<p>1. Do use multi-functional furniture pieces;</p>
<p>2. Do consider expandable/stackable tables that can be tucked away to save up space when not in use.</p>
<p>3. Do consider customizing your furniture pieces for smaller dimensions because readily-available furniture pieces in the market usually have standard dimensions.</p>
<p>4. Do create an open space layout. As much as possible, place larger pieces of furniture against the wall, even if sometimes that’s <a href="https://blog.froy.com/decorating-trends-to-avoid-8-common-interior-design-mistakes/">bad interior design</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Don’ts:</strong></p>
<p>1. Don’t block pathways and walkways with furniture and accessories because if you do, you’ll create a cramped layout.</p>
<p>2. Don’t visually display your stuff all throughout your space. If you own a lot of things, either declutter or develop an organizing system to hide them and to have a very sleek and clean interior.</p>
<p><strong>Hang wall art or tapestry with simple designs</strong></p>
<p>Decorating small spaces with hanging wall art or <a href="https://blog.froy.com/tapestry-ideas-for-decorating-your-home/">tapestry</a> will give some personality to the space. Remember to pick ones that are simple and light in design as to not avoid overcomplicating walls.</p>
<p>You can choose to hang a single large piece or a combination of a few smaller pieces. Either way, art and wall hangings have the ability to elevate the visual interest of your small apartment above ground. This helps lift the focus away from the clutter of your floor and to the much cleaner walls. If the art piece or tapestry are simple enough in design, it can act almost like a window and expand visual space.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/smallapartment/017e919dcbd5514798d7668ed5f92f8d.jpg" alt="" width="854" height="851" /></p>
<p><strong>Multi-purpose furniture</strong></p>
<p>Functionality is very crucial in decorating small spaces so consider using multi-purpose furniture pieces to save up space. You can use coffee tables with storage, a <a href="https://froy.com/collections/futons-sofa-beds">futon or sofa bed</a> instead of a traditional couch to serve as extra sleeping bed for guests, and a convertible folding desk (or you can have a foldable desk in tall shelves so as to hide them when not in use). You can also use an ottoman or a pouf in lieu or traditional coffee table to both maximize space and provide some warm cushiness – ottomans also commonly come with included internal storage.</p>
<p><strong>taller and wider curtains</strong></p>
<p>Curtains and draperies are often overlooked by many but this actually has a great impact in interior spaces. Instead of following the actual measurement of your windows, you should expand and lengthen the measurement of your curtains. By doing so, you provide more height to your small apartment and extend the visual space of your windows.</p>
<p>For example, if the ceiling height of your space is not high, you can do a floor to ceiling drapery. You can also make your windows appear wider by extending your curtain rod to at least about 300-400mm both sides.</p>
<p>Decorating small spaces is not really complicated. If you know how to play around with what you have, you don’t have to splurge so much. Just make this article your guide for small apartment decorating ideas and you’ll surely enjoy decorating!</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interior Design</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 16:50:29 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>COVID-19 and Architecture</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/architecture/covid-19-and-architecture</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/architecture/covid-19-and-architecture</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/covid-19-arch/Chayka-covid-home.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>Domestic Space</strong></p>
<p>Space is all we have to think about. For architects, it’s a soul-searching exercise, especially if you happen to live in a home you outfitted for yourself. The architect Koray Duman lives with his partner and their sixteen-month-old child in an apartment he designed, in the Lower East Side. Quarantine has led them to grow exhausted with the things they keep in the space, even though—with the exception of toddler accessories—they are relatively few. “You look at every detail of things. They limit you. If you have less you feel like you are more free, in a weird way,” Duman told me. Sustained scrutiny can breed discontent. Over the past two months, “interior designers got very busy,” he said. “People are, like, ‘I hate this space.’ ” Spending so long in one place might require an environment that can change more freely so that we don’t get bored. Usually a wall is static; “I don’t know that that’s necessary,” Duman said. “If it was on wheels, imagine how much fun you would have.”</p>
<p>Florian Idenburg and Jing Liu, a couple and the principals of the firm so-il—which has designed art museums, housing developments, and pop-up projects like the tent for the Frieze Art Fair—have been staying in their home, near the Brooklyn Navy Yard, with their two young daughters. It’s a bright white-walled duplex with open-plan common spaces. “Luckily, both our girls have their own rooms with thick doors,” Idenburg said. The arrangement comes in handy when the children have video-chat school sessions at the same time. Acoustic divisions have become more important while the family is crammed in together all day long, Idenburg noted. “The loft, the New York City typology, seems to be not the romantic thing at the moment. Everyone’s on Zoom calls.” A lack of privacy or the chance to move to a different room is harder to bear when bars, cafés, and stores can’t offer an escape.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/covid-19-arch/Chayka-covid-home.jpg" alt="" width="839" height="629" /></p>
<p><strong>Office Space</strong></p>
<p>Covid-19 calls for prophylactic design. Masks and gloves barricade our bodies like a second skin. Taped circles spaced six feet apart make sure we don’t contaminate others while standing in line at the grocery store. A Dutch restaurant built greenhouse-like glass booths around its outdoor tables to shield diners and waitstaff from each other. A German café tested out hats with pool noodles attached so that guests would know not to get too close to one another. A casino in Florida installed a thick sneeze guard of plastic on its poker tables, with clearance on the bottom for players’ hands.</p>
<p>We’ll have to be hyper-aware of the infrastructure of cleanliness. Are people taking their shoes off at the door? Is there a place by the door where you wash your hands? Le Corbusier solved the last problem by installing a freestanding sink in the entryway of his Villa Savoye, from 1931.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/covid-19-arch/Chayka-covid-office.jpg" alt="" width="838" height="558" /></p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:54:41 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Green Architecture</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/architecture/green-architecture</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/architecture/green-architecture</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/greenarchitecture/http___cdn.cnn.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_200420123610-16b-green-buildings-around-the-world-restricted.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>Common Characteristics of a "Green" Building</strong></p>
<p>The highest goal of green architecture is to be fully sustainable. Simply put, people do "green" things in order to achieve sustainability. Some architecture, like <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/magney-house-by-glenn-murcutt-178002">Glenn Murcutt's 1984 Magney House,</a> has been an experiment in green design for years. While most green buildings do not have all of the following features, green architecture and design may include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ventilation systems designed for efficient heating and cooling</li>
<li>Energy-efficient lighting and appliances (e.g., <a href="https://www.energystar.gov/">ENERGY STAR</a><sup>®</sup> products)</li>
<li>Water-saving plumbing fixtures</li>
<li>Landscaping with native vegetation and planned to maximize passive solar energy</li>
<li>Minimal harm to the natural habitat</li>
<li>Alternative renewable energy power sources such as solar power or wind power</li>
<li>Non-synthetic, non-toxic materials used inside and out</li>
<li>Locally-obtained woods and stone, eliminating long-haul transportation</li>
<li>Responsibly-harvested woods</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/adaptive-reuse-repurposing-old-buildings-178242">Adaptive reuse</a> of older buildings</li>
<li>Use of recycled <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/about-architectural-antiquities-and-salvage-175958">architectural salvage</a></li>
<li>Efficient use of space</li>
<li>Optimal location on the land, maximizing sunlight, winds, and natural sheltering</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/greenarchitecture/http___cdn.cnn.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_200316120121-13-green-buildings-around-the-world.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><strong>Looking to a Sustainable Future</strong></p>
<p>Green design has many related names and concepts associated with it, besides sustainable development. Some people emphasize the ecology and have adopted names like eco-design, eco-friendly architecture, and even arcology. Eco-tourism is a 21st-century trend, even if <a href="https://fthmb.tqn.com/ogD4kpXNCKVsTyMuQPkSJZvM-FQ=/green-eco-527161822-crop-5a24c587beba330037243de6.jpg">eco house designs might appear to be a bit non-traditional</a>.</p>
<p>A building can look beautiful and even be constructed from very expensive materials, but not be "green." Likewise, a building can be very "green" but visually unappealing. How do we get good architecture? How do we move toward what Roman architect Vitruvius suggested to be the <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/the-rules-of-architecture-177224">three rules of architecture</a>—to be well-built, useful by serving a purpose, and beautiful to look at?</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/greenarchitecture/http___cdn.cnn.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_200420123610-16b-green-buildings-around-the-world-restricted.jpg" alt="" /></p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:33:42 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Minimalist Design </title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/minimalist-design</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/minimalist-design</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/minimalistdesign/IN_27098014_0002.jpg" /></p>
<p>Minimalist interior design is very similar to modern interior design and involves using the bare essentials to create a simple and uncluttered space. It’s characterized by simplicity, clean lines, and a monochromatic palette with color used as an accent. It usually combines an open floor plan, lots of light, and functional furniture, and it focuses on the shape, color and texture of just a handful of essential elements.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/minimalistdesign/IN_27098014_0002.jpg" alt="" width="869" height="489" /></p>
<p>Elements of minimalist design</p>
<p>The minimalist approach uses only the essential elements: light, form and beautiful materials, usually in an <strong>open plan layout</strong>, to create a sense of freedom and relaxation. There is no excessive ornamentation and decoration. Instead, the few details that are used are uncomplicated and blend harmoniously into the setting. This might be in the form of a single artwork adorning a living room wall, or a beautiful vase on top of the dining room table.</p>
<p><strong>Minimalist furniture</strong> and accessories focus on functionality and practicality. Flat, smooth surfaces and strong, clean lines create bold statements that emphasize the essential nature of each item. You won't find highly patterned furnishings and accessories or highly detailed ornamentation. Instead, the focus is on the purity and simplicity of the shape and form.</p>
<p>Clear and clean benchtops and surfaces, bare walls with minimal artworks, and the elimination of clutter, including piles of papers and collections of knick-knacks are also essential to creating a minimalist space.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/minimalistdesign/robert-brown-interior-design-portfolio-interiors-family-room-media-1501110849-9469113-1557866371.jpg" alt="" width="845" height="634" /></p>
<p><strong>Challenges of Minimalist Design</strong></p>
<p><strong><em>"The biggest challenge is to make a space look warm and welcoming"</em></strong></p>
<p>Minimalist spaces are instantly recognizable for their crisp, clean, clutter-free and monochromatic look. The de-cluttering of space helps to de-clutter the mind and to create a sense of visual calm. However, some minimalist designs do run the risk of feeling a little soulless. To avoid this, and to ensure your minimalist-designed space also has a welcoming feel, there are a few small touches you can make. Whether it’s a kitchen, bedroom or living space, here are some ways to add warmth and color to your minimalist rooms.</p>
<p>When using a monochromatic color palette, a great way to bring warmth to the space is by incorporating different shades and mixing textures. For instance, the use of linen wallpaper and soft wool fabrics and rugs in the bedroom adds soothing warmth. In the bathroom, the texture and grain of tile patterns can add visual interest while still maintaining a neutral color palette, while wood accessories can soften stark, white or concrete elements. </p>
<p>Textiles add texture and provide added dimension and warmth to a space. Drapery, bedding, cushions, and area rugs in varying textiles such as linen, wool, and cotton are just a few examples of how you can add warmth and comfort to a room while maintaining a <strong>minimalist style</strong>.</p>
<p> </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interior Design</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:37:15 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pop Art Interior Design Style </title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/pop-art-interior-design-style</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/pop-art-interior-design-style</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/popart/pop-art-interior-style.jpg" /></p>
<p>Inspired by advertising campaigns, billboards and television artists such as Andy Warhol, Roy Lichtenstein and Richard Hamilton turned to mediocrity. As part of the so-called anti-art - the campaign, they released the banal images of famous actors and transformed into exciting new art form.</p>
<p>Pop art interior design style is very emotional and energetic, so it is particularly close to young people who are ready to live in perpetual motion.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/popart/pop-art-interior-style.jpg" alt="" width="747" height="498" /></p>
<p>Bright colorful interior exhibitions are made of plastic, synthetic fibers, functional objects of catchy form, repetitive accessories, posters, and inexpensive popular souvenirs such as the plush heart.</p>
<p>1.Identical items of different sizes are placed at different levels.</p>
<p>2.large print or photo on the glass with a recognizable image can be placed in the center of the space: portraits of religious figures or products (a portrait of Che Guevara or advertising of Coca-Cola in the bedroom above the headboard perfectly match the style preferences).</p>
<p>3.Carpets with the logo of a well-known company or expressly synthetic animal skins, wall tiles with the repeating and recognizable patterns.</p>
<p>4.Furniture – bright colors, with a catchy pattern, perhaps – with glossy surfaces or plastic.<img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/popart/680d80d5-17f9-418c-89b6-801164c441811.jpg" alt="" width="747" height="560" /></p>
<p>The walls, ceiling, and floor do not carry background notional load visually, they may merge into one decoration conceived by the artist. The pop art style in the interior allows acid colors that blend with the white, contrasting items together at the same time. A sense of proportion is determined only by your ability for a long staying in such screaming scenery.</p>
<p>1.Optimum division of the walls by color is when one wall remains cream or <a href="https://www.smalldesignideas.com/beige-color-interior-decoration-ideas-proper-combinations.html">beige</a>, and it accommodates the mirror of unusual shape or stylized print, the other two are painted in bright tones, but in tune with each other, the fourth – the one that includes a door or window – in simple ornamental technology.</p>
<p>2.The ceiling can be multileveled and asymmetrical with colorful lighting as well as to have a glossy plane surface.</p>
<p>3.The floor is the most neutral part of the composition. But you can possibly meet a bright carpet (or restrained color with a chaotic pattern) here.</p>
<p>4.The furniture amount is minimal. However, it has futuristic, unusual shape, squat, and deserving special reviewing.</p>
<p>5.Accessories are plastic, chrome, but always of amusing form. For example, in the form of a female silhouette or comic book heroes.</p>
<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/popart/361.jpg" alt="" width="736" height="502" /></p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interior Design</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:16:49 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Balance in interior design</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/balance-in-interior-design</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/stories/interior-design/balance-in-interior-design</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/Balance/image14-2.jpg" /></p>
<p>Of course, there will be other elements at play, but getting the balance right within any room is important to how it will make you feel when you are in it.</p>
<p>Planning out your spaces can be easy if you understand the principles of applying balance.</p>
<p>It is key to making a room look visually stable by the simple placement of furniture, accessories, the use of color and other elements such as form, and size.</p>
<p>Without it you will end up a room that feels, and looks uncomfortable to be in.</p>
<p>There are basically three different types of balance: <strong>Symmetry, Asymmetry</strong> and <strong>Radial</strong>.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Symmetrical Balance</span></h4>
<p>Symmetrical balance is achieved when items are actually repeated or mirrored along a central axis.</p>
<p>This type of balance is frequently seen in nature, our own bodies included.</p>
<p>Symmetry is common in interior design and can portray a feeling of stability, calmness and dignity; however, can also be seen as static, dull and unimaginative.</p>
<p>Symmetry can be achieved through the use of pattern, arrangement of furniture, fixtures and millwork, and through the application of color<strong>.</strong></p>
<p><strong><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/Balance/484bdd2eceb9bd3c7e3703d926982eb5.jpg" alt="" width="177" height="247" /></strong></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Asymmetrical Balance</span></h4>
<p>Asymmetrical balance relates very strongly to the visual weight of objects.</p>
<p>Rather than repeating the same item within a space to achieve balance, in this case we are using different elements with a similar perceived weight to achieve balance on the opposing axis.</p>
<p>As stated above, complex shapes often feel heavier and for that reason are commonly used to achieve asymmetrical balance.</p>
<p>Asymmetrical interiors tend to feel more dynamic and less rigid because in these spaces a variety of objects types are working together to create balance.</p>
<p>This form of balance can be more difficult to achieve it often requires an “eye for design”.<br /><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/Balance/1907f964bc37139cf57d1ecb122fb76a.jpg" alt="" width="315" height="315" /></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Radial Balance</span><strong><br /></strong></h4>
<p>Just as it sounds radial balance is almost circular – distributed arrangement of items around a central point either extending outward or inward.</p>
<p>Common examples of radial balance translated to the interior environment include chairs centered around a table, the structure of a circular rotunda, or even a circular lighting fixture.</p>
<p>If you wish to create focus on a central item, applying radial balance (so that the your attention is directed inward) is a great way to achieve this.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Blog/Balance/499bcd5ee7ca17a5f937bf5179106e61.jpg" alt="" width="221" height="271" /></strong></p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Interior Design</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 13:17:44 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
