<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Mugo - Awards</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://mugo.ge/news/awards</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:08:16 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://mugo.ge/news/awards?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (Mugo Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Restaurant &quot;Kalaki&quot; has won German Design Award 2020</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/awards/restaurant-qalaqi-has-won-german-design-award-2020</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/awards/restaurant-qalaqi-has-won-german-design-award-2020</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/11/GermanAward.jpg" /></p><p>We are pleased to announce that the restaurant "Kalaki" has been awarded the German Design Award 2020 for excellent architecture and interior design.</p>

<p>We are pleased to announce that the restaurant "Kalaki" has been awarded the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="https://www.german-design-award.com/en.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GERMAN DESIGN AWARD</a></strong></span> 2020 for excellent architecture and interior design.</p>
<p>The ceremony took place on 07 February 2020 in the context of the Ambiente fair in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>The statement of the Jury regarding the restaurant "Kalaki" project reads "The replica of a classic Tbilisi courtyard and the painted sky create a unique and distinctive atmosphere. Exclusive and extraordinary".</p>
<p>The German Design Award directly contributes to overall commercial success.</p>
<p>Prizes are awarded to projects that truly represent pioneering contributions to the German and international design landscape.</p>
<p>The highly esteemed, international jury guarantees this. The German Design Award identifies and presents unique design trends: a competition that advances the design-oriented scene.</p>
<p>Earlier the same project had wan a Golden A' Design Award in Interior Space and Exhibition Design Category by the International Design Academy, the grand jury panel of the A' Design Award &amp; Competition which consists of internationally influential press members, established designers, leading academics and prominent entrepreneurs.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (გიორგი სულიაშვილი(DEV))</author>
			<category>Awards</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:17:32 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has received Passive House Designer Certification</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/awards/passive-house-designer-certification</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/awards/passive-house-designer-certification</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/8/PassiveHouseCert.jpg" /></p><p>After a long time working on energy-efficient projects, at Mugo, we take a step further with the<strong><em> </em>Passive House Designer Certification</strong><strong>. </strong></p>

<p>After a long time working on energy-efficient projects, at Mugo, we take a step further with the<strong><em> </em>Passive House Designer Certification</strong><strong>. </strong></p>
<p>Our company's architect has been certified by the International Passive House Association, which means, that Mugo can receive inquiries on Passive Houses, therefore adding Georgia to the map of passive houses worldwide, contributing to the global scale architecture.</p>
<p>Pass­ive House build­ings are en­ergy ef­fi­cient build­ings that provide a high level of thermal comfort and extremely low energy consumption.</p>
<p>They may not look any dif­fer­ent from oth­er build­ings, but good plan­ning, as well as care­ful ex­e­cu­tion of the de­tails, high-quality construction and precise implementation, which reflects our<strong> </strong>work philosophy, is es­sen­tial for constructing such pro­jects.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Awards</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:13:08 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Restaurant &quot;Kalaki&quot; has been awarded the Golden A' Design Award in 'Interior Space and Exhibition Design Category'</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/awards/a-design-award-and-competitions-2</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/awards/a-design-award-and-competitions-2</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/4/Kalaki.jpg" /></p><p>We are pleased to announce that the restaurant "Kalaki" has been awarded the Golden A' Design Award in Interior Space and Exhibition Design Category.</p>

<p>We are pleased to announce that restaurant "Kalaki" has been awarded the Golden A' Design Award in Interior Space and Exhibition Design Category by the International Design Academy, the grand jury panel of the A' Design Award &amp; Competition which consists of internationally influential press members, established designers, leading academics and prominent entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>The A' Design Award is the World's most influential and largest design accolade, presented each year in Italy.</p>
<p>It is a great honor for us to receive this prestigious award and to be selected amongst the participants from 200 countries.</p>
<p>A 'Award aims to provide a fair, ethical and competitive platform for companies, designers and innovators from all spheres of design.</p>
<p>The award-winning company "Mugo" operates on the Georgian market since 2014 and creates an architectural quality based on innovations and experiences.</p>
<p>The company specializes in providing commercial and residential sectors with architecture, interior design and construction services.</p>
<p>The restaurant "Kalaki" has been launched in May 2018  and is located in Kostava Street - one of the oldest neighborhoods in Tbilisi with diverse architectural styles.</p>
<p>The architecture of the project was carefully thought through and detailed for the contextual setting and creates a classical and sophisticated environment within the texture of the old town.</p>
<p>Award-winning designs will be exhibited in Italy, and the architects will be awarded on June 28 in Como, Italy.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Awards</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 13:25:03 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
