<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Mugo - Completed</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://mugo.ge/news/completed</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:08:21 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://mugo.ge/news/completed?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (Mugo Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Tabidze Apartment has been broadcasted on national TV show</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/completed/completed-project-on-tabidze-street</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/completed/completed-project-on-tabidze-street</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Abashidze-Apartment/1.jpg" /></p><p>One of Mugo's projects - interior design of the apartment on Tabidze street has been broadcasted on the national TV show - "Sheni Dila with Salome Dadunashvili".</p>

<p>The project on Tabidze street that has been designed by "Mugo" was <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="https://youtu.be/hAYRcE7LNaw">broadcasted</a></strong></span> on TV program devoted to interior design. </p>
<p>With the aim to reinterpret traditional design standards, the apartment features the intersection of spaces, surfaces and compositions that are functional and create a bespoke visual effect.</p>
<p>One of the main challenges of the planning process was to create an interior where all of the rooms would have access to the spectacular views of the greenery of "Vake Park" and benefit from ample sunlight.</p>
<p>Modern minimalism is present in every single area of this luxury interior, where modern and traditional materials meet to create a bespoke environment, that delivers comfort.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (სოფო კოტრიკაძე)</author>
			<category>Completed</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:41:45 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has completed interior design project for private apartment</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/completed/mugo-has-completed-interior-design-project-for-private-apartment</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/completed/mugo-has-completed-interior-design-project-for-private-apartment</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/10/InteriorDesign.jpg" /></p><p>The design of the given apartment balances classical and modern styles. Used decorative materials harmoniously merge to create an elegant and comfortable ambiance.</p>

<p>The design of the given apartment balances classical and modern styles.</p>
<p>Used decorative materials harmoniously merge to create an elegant and comfortable ambiance.</p>
<p>The overall style and integrity is remained besides the use of different color pallets, materials and textures in different rooms.</p>
<p>A lightweight, refined style used in the design, combined with a variety of materials and color pallets, creates a peaceful, pleasant and unique environment.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Completed</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:20:10 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo submitted new project in Kansas, U.S.</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/completed/mugo-submitted-new-project-in-kansas-u-s</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/completed/mugo-submitted-new-project-in-kansas-u-s</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/9/ChestersChophouseWine-Bar.jpg" /></p><p>Mugo designed a project for renovating steakhouse "Chester’s Chophouse &amp; Wine Bar" in Kansas, U.S.</p>

<p>The main goal of the project was to provide renovated ambiance to the current steakhouse - "Chester’s Chophouse &amp; Wine Bar" and at the same time preserve its old characteristics.</p>
<p>It's noteworthy, that in one of the areas of the restaurant are exhibited Georgian artworks.</p>
<p>While working on the project, the total area of the restaurant was enlarged, different areas were integrated via moving decorative dividers and was introduced wine degustation area.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Completed</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 22:55:00 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Green Facade for Radisson Collection Tsinandali - Innovative Structure</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/completed/green-facade-for-radisson-collection-tsinandali-innovative-structure</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/completed/green-facade-for-radisson-collection-tsinandali-innovative-structure</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/1/Tsinandali.jpg" /></p><p>Mugo performed Green Facade construction works for Radisson Collection Tsinandali. This made the hotel building the first Facade in Georgia fully covered in greenery.</p>

<p>Mugo performed Green Facade construction works for Radisson Collection Tsinandali.</p>
<p>This made the hotel building the first Facade in Georgia fully covered in greenery.</p>
<p>The green facade is the most striking element of the building it contributes to bringing nature into resort's landscape.</p>
<p>When guests approach Radisson Collection Tsinandali, they may feel like diving into a nature through the green facade.</p>
<p>Different species used on the facade contribute to biodiversity and a cleaner environment.</p>
<p>Volume of the building is covered by metal construction, on which the composition of planted elements is fixed.</p>
<p>The green facade allows Radisson Hotel to absorb tons of CO2, scrubbing the air for healthier living conditions for both visitors of the hotel and the wider city.</p>
<p>It reduces energy consumption: protects the building from harsh sunlight offering solutions for the serious urban problems.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Completed</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 17:50:05 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
