<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Mugo - Current Works</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:08:19 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://mugo.ge/news/current-works?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (Mugo Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has started to work on the skyscraper project in Batumi, Georgia </title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/skyscraper-in-batumi</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/skyscraper-in-batumi</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/BATUMI.jpg" /></p><p>We are glad to announce that <strong>Mugo</strong> has been assigned to start a new skyscraper project in Batumi, Georgia.</p>

<p>The skyscraper project in Batumi is a high-rise, mixed-use development, which will be the highest building in the region. The project consists of residential apartments, apart-hotels, a 5-star brand hotel, several brand shops, offices, co-working spaces, a nightclub, pool, etc. </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 12:51:57 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo will be designing interior for the hotel Canopy by Hilton Tbilisi</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-will-be-designing-interior-for-canopy-by-hilton-tbilisi</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-will-be-designing-interior-for-canopy-by-hilton-tbilisi</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/16/canopy-by-h.jpg" /></p><p>Mugo has been assigned to design the interior of Canopy By Hilton Tbilisi.</p>

<p>Mugo has been assigned to design the interior of Canopy By Hilton Tbilisi. </p>
<p>An upper-upscale lifestyle 114 room hotel will be located at Kote Abkhazi Street. The site has a heritage status.</p>
<p>The Canopy brand standards envision having the local context and local neighborhood of the project area define the overall interior design of the hotel.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 17:41:22 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has been assigned to design interior for visitor center in Tsalka municipality </title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-has-been-assigned-to-design-interior-for-visitor-center-in-tsalka-municipality</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-has-been-assigned-to-design-interior-for-visitor-center-in-tsalka-municipality</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/14/DJI_0053.jpg" /></p><p>The project envisions designing interiors for the visitor center and two restaurants near Dashbashi canyon.</p>

<p>The project envisions designing interiors for the visitor center and two restaurants near Dashbashi canyon. </p>
<p>Also, create landscape design and the project of architectural lighting.</p>
<p>The design takes into consideration the local context, project territory and the purpose of the project area.</p>
<p>Colors, textures and shapes that are common to the project area will be reflected in the design.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 16:53:31 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>First visual images have been released for private house design project in Tbilisi</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/first-visual-images-have-been-released-for-private-house-design-project-in-tbilisi</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/first-visual-images-have-been-released-for-private-house-design-project-in-tbilisi</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/15/small.jpg" /></p><p>Mugo is working on a new project for private house design in Tbilisi.</p>

<p>Mugo is working on a new project for private house design in Tbilisi. </p>
<p>The living space of an individual house project is tailored to the needs of the modern family with a reasonably distributed layout.</p>
<p>The unique color scheme, different natural materials, and wood create an elegant and sophisticated space, which is enriched with decorative elements.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:27:47 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has been assigned for developing recreational settlement project in the  Village Tsemi</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-has-been-assigned-for-developing-recreational-settlement-project-in-the-village-tsemi</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-has-been-assigned-for-developing-recreational-settlement-project-in-the-village-tsemi</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/viber_image_2021-01-18_14-58-20.jpg" /></p><p>The project of the recreational settlement envisions the development of the area in the village Tsemi, former children's summer camp territory.</p>

<p>The project of the recreational settlement envisions the development of the area in the village Tsemi, former children's summer camp territory.</p>
<p>The project is to be developed on a five-hectare plot of land, with a European mountain town-type district, pedestrianized commercial development and sports infrastructure.</p>
<p>From 30 to 40, 3-4-story penthouse-type buildings with a unified architectural look will be built on the territory.</p>
<p>Cafe-restaurants, shops and other commercial facilities will be arranged on the ground floors of the buildings.</p>
<p>According to the architectural plan, the project buildings will form a unified architectural ensemble and harmoniously blend into the existing environment, which can already be seen from the spatial-volume conceptual model.</p>
<p>Sports infrastructure will play an important role in the functioning of the hotel complex.</p>
<p>In the north-eastern zone of the plot, a sports complex will be built with an indoor basketball hall, a tennis court, a fitness hall, and all other necessary spaces for functioning.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 19:27:10 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo is completing restaurant design in Gori</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-is-completing-restaurant-design-in-gori</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-is-completing-restaurant-design-in-gori</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/6/gorigori.jpg" /></p><p>Mugo has been assigned to design a restaurant project in Gori region, village Karaleti.</p>

<p>Mugo has been assigned to design a restaurant project in Gori region, village Karaleti.</p>
<p>The total project area consists of 10002 m2. The construction part is divided into 3 areas and completely assemble 2935 m2.</p>
<p>Natural materials and color pallets are being selected to naturally blend into the given context.</p>
<p>Natural materials play an important role in the design of the interior, as with the interplay of wood, metal, natural stone, marble and textile memorable and distinguishable appearance is achieved.</p>
<p>Each part of the interior, including VIP rooms are designed to deliver bespoke design and special character.  </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 12:28:22 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has been assigned to design a new hotel in Tsinandali</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-has-been-assigned-to-design-a-new-hotel-in-tsinandali</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-has-been-assigned-to-design-a-new-hotel-in-tsinandali</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/20200909_122937.jpg" /></p><p>Mugo has been assigned to design a new hotel in Tsinandali.</p>

<p>Mugo has been assigned to design a new hotel in Tsinandali.</p>
<p>The hotel territory will cover 20 Hectares and with the branded hotels will feature a modern wine factory, distiller, and vineyard with precious Georgian and European breeds. </p>
<p>The main concept will be bringing architecture close to nature by minimal intervention in the landscape.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 19:07:44 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has started design project for the restaurant &quot;Aviator&quot; in Gudauri</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-has-started-design-project-for-loft-gudauri-restaurant</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/mugo-has-started-design-project-for-loft-gudauri-restaurant</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/13/gudauri-.jpg" /></p><p>Mugo has been assigned to design the restaurant "Aviator" of the existing hotel "Gudauri Loft", which should be redesigned and enlarged. </p>

<p>The hotel "Gudauri Loft" is located at the heart of Gudauri ski resort and is placed very close to the first ski slope.</p>
<p>The existing area of 210 sq.m will be enlarged to 355 sq.m. and designed to bring the special ambiance of loft with the accents from the aviator theme.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (სოფო კოტრიკაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 13:46:07 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>First visual images have been released for interior design project in Tbilisi</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/our-latest-interior-design-project-in-tbilisi</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/our-latest-interior-design-project-in-tbilisi</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Apartment-Interior-Tbilisi-2020/saxl787878i.jpg" /></p><p>We are happy to share our latest interior design project in Tbilisi. The modern classic apartment interior design features a dynamic variation of modern accents embellished with classical elements.</p>

<p>We are happy to share our latest interior design project in Tbilisi.</p>
<p>The modern classic apartment interior design features a dynamic and eye-catching variation of modern accents embellished with classical design elements.</p>
<p>With large windows that let in ample sunlight &amp; a mostly neutral palette articulated in lush materials like velvet and marble, this home feels is positively royal. </p>
<p>Except for the design approaches, this apartment is "smart", combining lighting, heating/cooling, air conditioning and security smart systems.</p>
<p>A lightweight, refined style used in the design, combined with a variety of materials and color pallets, creates a classic, pleasant, and unique environment.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 16:42:19 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has started to design the facade for the hotel &quot;Villa Godoli&quot; in Kakheti</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/facade-design-for-hotel-villa-godoli-in-kakheti</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/current-works/facade-design-for-hotel-villa-godoli-in-kakheti</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/12/VillaGodoli.jpg" /></p><p>Mugo has started to work on the facade design of the hotel “Villa Godoli” in Kakheti Region, Georgia.</p>

<p>Mugo has started to work on the facade design of the hotel “Villa Godoli” in Kakheti Region, Georgia. </p>
<p>The modern interpretation of ethnic style introduces Kakheti’s architecture to its visitors, which is characterized by monolithic facades, strict lines and textures.</p>
<p>This facade represents the inspiration and commitment resulted from strong links between ethnicity and modernity, while its’ design comes in line with the overall ambiance and designation of the hotel. As a model of locally-inspired design, the hotel will set out to shine a light on Kakheti’s rich history and build the region’s profile as an emerging travel hotspot.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Current Works</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 12:47:03 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
