<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Mugo - Nomination</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://mugo.ge/news/nomination</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:08:22 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://mugo.ge/news/nomination?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (Mugo Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Restaurant &quot;Kalaki&quot; is nominated for A' Design Award and Competitions</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/nomination/restaurant-kalaki-is-nominated-for-a-design-award-and-competitions</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/nomination/restaurant-kalaki-is-nominated-for-a-design-award-and-competitions</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/2/Awards.jpg" /></p><p>Restaurant "Kalaki" is nominated for A' Design Award and Competitions. A' Design Award is the worlds' largest and most diffused annual design competition.</p>

<p>Restaurant "Kalaki" is nominated for A' Design Award and Competitions.</p>
<p>A' Design Award is the worlds' largest and most diffused design competition reaching over 200 countries each year.</p>
<p>The Award is organized and awarded annually and internationally in a wide range of categories to create awareness for good design.</p>
<p>The mission of the A' Award and Competition is to provide a fair, ethical and competitive platform for companies, designers and innovators from all design fields with different experience levels, diverse disciplines and market focus to compete on, while providing them a global audience to showcase their success and talents to.</p>
<p>A' Design Award and Competitions, aims to highlight the excellent qualifications of best designs, design concepts and design oriented products.</p>
<p>A' Design Award and Competitions are organized and awarded annually and internationally in multiple categories to reach a wide, design-oriented audience.</p>
<p>Restaurant "Kalaki" is nominated in a category - A' Interior Space, Retail and Exhibition Design.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Nomination</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:28:52 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
