<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Mugo - Submission</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://mugo.ge/news/submission</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:08:18 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://mugo.ge/news/submission?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (Mugo Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>The renovation of the recreational space near Pansheti Village, in Kazbegi Municipality has been planned</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/submission/the-renovation-of-the-recreational-space-near-pansheti-village-in-kazbegi-municipality-has-been-planned</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/submission/the-renovation-of-the-recreational-space-near-pansheti-village-in-kazbegi-municipality-has-been-planned</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/Projects/Recreational-Space-Near-Pansheti-Village/111.jpg" /></p><p><strong>Mugo</strong> has designed the renovation project of recreational space in Kazbegi, near Pansheti village, assigned by Kazbegi Municipality.</p>

<p><strong>Mugo</strong> has designed the renovation project of recreational space in Kazbegi, near Pansheti village, assigned by Kazbegi Municipality.</p>
<p>The project space represents a public park, with the project site area of 3 603 m<sup>2</sup>. Pansheti park is represented by different recreational spaces.</p>
<p>One of them is the swimming pool, which is filled up with the natural spring with healing properties, presented in the area.</p>
<p>The architecture of the recreational space suits to the nature, mountains, rocks and alpine zone of Kazbegi.</p>
<p>The pool and the surrounding area are well-equipped to the highest standards.</p>
<p>The main pool for adults, featuring a pergola and sunbathing area transforms into the closed pool in winter.</p>
<p>The project area also includes children’s playgrounds with a kid’s pool, multifunctional sports space and administrative building.</p>
<p>Access to the building and movement within the territory is adapted for people with disabilities.</p>
<p>Well organized space, tasting and collecting of drinking water is possible for 12 months for Kazbegi district residents and tourists.</p>
<p>The surrounding areas will be of great interest to the local community in terms of business development.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Submission</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 17:48:12 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The contest for the project of the Headquarters of the National Bank of Georgia</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/submission/the-contest-for-the-project-of-the-headquarters-of-the-national-bank-of-georgia</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/submission/the-contest-for-the-project-of-the-headquarters-of-the-national-bank-of-georgia</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/6/HQNBankGeorgia.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>"GLMV Architecture Inc."</strong> which collaborates with <strong>Mugo LLC</strong> has won the contest which considered the project of the Headquarter of the National Bank of Georgia.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>"GLMV Architecture Inc."</strong> which collaborates with <strong>Mugo LLC</strong> has won the contest held by National Bank of Georgia which considered the project of the Headquarter of the National Bank of Georgia.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Mugo will perform the role of a technical architect in the implementation of this proposal.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The main concept of the new Headquarters of the National bank of Georgia project is the synthesis of its shape, aesthetics, ideology, and function.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The ideology of the building is related to its geometric shape of the circle, which is considered to be a continuous source of eternity and constant existence.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The notion of collaboration flows into the layout and planning of each floor of the building.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Each level is conveniently connected via the ramp, along the atrium and provides a comfortable and ample solution for the internal circulation. Bespoke architectural layout purpose fits the bank regulations including the furniture is being designed. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">One of the key elements of the building is panoramic (smart) lift systems located in the atrium offering bank employees minimum waiting time and remarkable trip while enjoying atrium space filled with natural daylight and views.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In establishing the functional and architectural character of the project, the concept of determining energy efficiency criteria played one of the main roles. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The concept is represented with the system of solar panels, which leads to the extraction of a large amount of electricity by working of the heat pumps. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">About  75% of the kinetic building's facade membrane is provided with stainless steel shutters, which are connected to lighting sensors and automatically open and close according to the sunlight intensity.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The selection of the entire glazing system of the facade is based on sun position and relative U and G parameters of the glazing, proving maximum cooling and heating effect.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The striking facade of the building is defined by an externally located three two-story atrium spaces revealing to the city an internal content and providing an external connection to the urban texture of the historic neighborhood.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Submission</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 12:39:47 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mugo has won the competition to design a park in Gergeti, Kazbegi Region</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/submission/mugo</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/submission/mugo</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/5/Gergeti.jpg" /></p><p>We are happy to announce, that "<strong>Mugo"</strong> has won the competition to design a park in Gergeti, Kazbegi region, held by Kazbegi Municipality. </p>

<p>We are happy to announce, that "<strong>Mugo"</strong> has won the competition to design a park in Gergeti, Kazbegi region, held by Kazbegi Municipality.</p>
<p>One of the most important areas of Gergeti park’s project is the complex of buildings of the multifunctional cultural center, consisting of:</p>
<p><strong>+</strong> Ethnographic Museum</p>
<p><strong>+</strong> Exhibition hall</p>
<p><strong>+</strong> Space of education of arts</p>
<p><strong>+</strong> Literary cafe</p>
<p><strong>+</strong> Conference room</p>
<p>During the park design process, an existing monument has been preserved, which is located at the center of the complex’s buildings.</p>
<p>The idea of the project’s architectural concept is based on the character and shape of the local landscape, which is presented by harmonious fusion of the buildings to the natural environment, which has been successfully reached by designing unique structures and landscaped roofs of these buildings.</p>
<p>The complex of the cultural center will add particular importance to Gergeti Park as well as to the Kazbegi Region, which will become one of the key landmarks in the future.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (გიორგი სულიაშვილი(DEV))</author>
			<category>Submission</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 17:51:16 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Multifunctional Center in the heart of Tbilisi is currently discussed by City Hall</title>
			<link>https://mugo.ge/news/submission/huge-multifunction-center-in-the-heart-of-tbilisi-is-currently-discussed-by-city-hall</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mugo.ge/news/submission/huge-multifunction-center-in-the-heart-of-tbilisi-is-currently-discussed-by-city-hall</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://mugo.ge/images/News/3/AragviCenter.jpg" /></p><p>The concept of multifunctional center on the territory behind the Circus, which includes shopping center, hotel, residential buildings, office and recreational area.</p>

<p>The concept of multifunctional center on the territory behind the Circus, which includes shopping center, hotel, residential buildings, office and recreational area.</p>
<p>The complex project is currently being discussed at the Tbilisi City Hall Architecture Service. The proposed concept of buildings aims to maximize the environment, rebuild and develop green recreational zones.</p>
<p>From its central location on the Mtkvari Embankment, the site is perfectly placed to capture the unique beauty and personality of Tbilisi. </p>
<p>The idea of ​​the architectural concept of the project is based on the nature of the local landscape, which envisages the maximum harmonic recording of the existing environment.</p>
<p>Configuration, proportion and geometry of buildings defined by the  existing context and relief.</p>
<p>It is also expressed in the formation of an architectural context that is reflected in its forms, textures and colors.</p>
<p>The design volumes repeat the form of the hills, characteristic for the relief and landscape of the area.</p>
<p>Proposed color scheme would seamlessly match surrounding natural landscape and will blend into existing site.</p>
<p>Special consideration is given to all existing trees and plantation on site to preserve and maintain at maximum extinct.</p>
<p>The multifunctional complex consists of 4 volumes located on 4 storey podium: hotel, shopping center, office space and 2 living capacity.</p>
<p>The Shopping Podium - is approximately 40-45 000 sq.m.  unifying podium for the whole complex. The building comprises a semi-open construction of 5 floors, with huge atrium in the center, which is open to the atmosphere.</p>
<p>The podium fills a large cavity currently formed in the location and repeats and continues existing contour of the relief.</p>
<p>The project blends within the landscape… providing no border within the nature and surroundings.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@mugo.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Submission</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 01:01:53 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
