<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Spectrum - Architecture</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:08:25 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (Spectrum Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>Must-Know Tips for Building an Energy-Efficient Home</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/must-know-tips-for-building-an-energy-efficient-home</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/must-know-tips-for-building-an-energy-efficient-home</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/ENERGYSAVINGDEVICES/energy-effiecint-house.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>All About Location</strong></p>
<p>While building an <strong>energy-efficient home</strong>, location, shape, and construction materials are prime considerations that will significantly influence the heating and cooling requirements. The maximum use of passive solar energy gain in winters and reduction of the heat gain during summers is the ideal scenario. It is achieved by optimizing the location, orientation, and landscaping of the home.</p>
<p>Home orientation determines how much sun your house will be getting.  This has a direct impact on your home’s temperature.</p>
<p>Design the home to take advantage of different sun angles. The midday sun is at a low angle in winter and a high angle in summer. Based on this, position your home to reduce heating and cooling expenses<strong>. </strong>Homes situated on the south side of the street-facing north get a lot of sunlight at the back of the house. Homes on the north side get shade during the summer afternoons in their backyards.  Similarly, if you’re living in a colder climate, you’d want to choose your windows’ location to be able to absorb maximum sunlight. South-facing homes capture sunlight in the winter while blocking it during summer.</p>
<p><strong>Ventilation Systems</strong></p>
<p>A well-designed ventilation system for an energy-efficient house doesn’t only provide comfort but also helps in energy saving by preventing the overuse of electrical appliances used for heating and cooling purposes. Moreover, <a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/blog/home-ventilation/">home ventilation</a> also filters out contaminated air. The simplest form of ventilation systems are windows and mechanical systems with fans used to keep the interior pleasant. Your home design should ensure healthy and natural ventilation.</p>
<p>The ventilation system is an integral part of your energy-efficient house design because it moves air and moisture across the building envelope’s barrier, and sometimes it also moves heat. A well-thought-out ventilation system can significantly minimize your overall energy usage and help make your home more energy-efficient.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/ENERGYSAVINGDEVICES/energy-effiecint-house.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><strong>Energy Saving Devices</strong></p>
<p>With the progress and advancement in technology, the selection of relevant smart devices can help you in <a href="https://paylesspower.com/blog/energy-saving-tips/">saving and optimizing your home energy</a>. Such devices use minimum energy to function as compared to regular appliances, thus further reducing your electricity bills. An energy-efficient home needs to be smart to give a good return on investment and save money in the longer run.</p>
<p>You can utilize <a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/">smart AC controllers</a>, smart thermostats, smart bulbs, smart blinds, kitchen appliances, etc., to equip your smart home. Taking the example of smart AC controllers, they function by regulating your air conditioner usage according to your usage habits throughout the day helping you save 25% on your cooling and heating bills. They can also be coupled with other <a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/blog/10-best-smart-home-climate-control-appliances/">smart home climate control appliances</a> connected with Alexa or Google Home for further benefits.</p>
<p><strong>Design for Water Conservation</strong></p>
<p>An increasing number of energy-efficient houses are incorporating water-saving systems. For instance, homeowners are going for <a href="https://www.choice.com.au/home-improvement/water/saving-water/articles/guide-to-greywater-systems">greywater recycling systems</a>. Greywater is the waste water from showers, sinks, laundry tubs, and washing machines. You can have a diversion system installed that carries the greywater from your washing machine to your bathroom or your garden.</p>
<p>This system can <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2014/jul/21/greywater-systems-can-they-really-reduce-your-bills">decrease your water usage by about 50%</a>, helping reduce your water bills.</p>
<p>Moreover, you can also save water during the shower and washing dishes by incorporating new technology in your house. New low-flow water fixtures in the kitchen and showers reduce the amount of water coming out of them but distribute it more evenly.</p>
<p><strong>Roofing Materials</strong></p>
<p>The roofing material is another important consideration when building an energy-efficient home. The material used for the roof of your house can absorb less heat by deflecting the sunlight, thus maintaining a constant temperature of your home. The choice of roofing materials makes a difference in overall energy efficiency. The materials used to build the roof help you with energy conservation, decrease air pollution and greenhouse gas emissions, and keep your home cool without air conditioning.</p>
<p>Initially, the selection of a roof could be expensive, but in the long run, it pays back and reduces your bill by regulating the temperature of your home during summers.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Go Solar</strong></p>
<p>Solar Panels can help build energy-efficient homes. If your area is exposed to the sun throughout the year, then solar panels will surely reduce your electricity bills. These panels don’t require extensive maintenance, so it’s a one-time investment that saves you from a lot of hassle and makes you self-sufficient.</p>
<p>Solar panels are an environmentally friendly option since solar energy is converted into electrical energy, reducing harmful greenhouse gases that contribute to global warming. Once you have installed solar panels, you can use the energy for a host of different uses, such as a solar heater for heating water, bulbs, and practically any home appliance.</p>
<p> <img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/ENERGYSAVINGDEVICES/solar-panels.jpg" alt="" width="892" height="502" /></p>
<p> </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 16:02:12 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>COVID-19 and Architecture</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/covid-19-and-architecture</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/covid-19-and-architecture</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/covid-19-arch/Chayka-covid-home.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>Domestic Space</strong></p>
<p>Space is all we have to think about. For architects, it’s a soul-searching exercise, especially if you happen to live in a home you outfitted for yourself. The architect Koray Duman lives with his partner and their sixteen-month-old child in an apartment he designed, in the Lower East Side. Quarantine has led them to grow exhausted with the things they keep in the space, even though—with the exception of toddler accessories—they are relatively few. “You look at every detail of things. They limit you. If you have less you feel like you are more free, in a weird way,” Duman told me. Sustained scrutiny can breed discontent. Over the past two months, “interior designers got very busy,” he said. “People are, like, ‘I hate this space.’ ” Spending so long in one place might require an environment that can change more freely so that we don’t get bored. Usually a wall is static; “I don’t know that that’s necessary,” Duman said. “If it was on wheels, imagine how much fun you would have.”</p>
<p>Florian Idenburg and Jing Liu, a couple and the principals of the firm so-il—which has designed art museums, housing developments, and pop-up projects like the tent for the Frieze Art Fair—have been staying in their home, near the Brooklyn Navy Yard, with their two young daughters. It’s a bright white-walled duplex with open-plan common spaces. “Luckily, both our girls have their own rooms with thick doors,” Idenburg said. The arrangement comes in handy when the children have video-chat school sessions at the same time. Acoustic divisions have become more important while the family is crammed in together all day long, Idenburg noted. “The loft, the New York City typology, seems to be not the romantic thing at the moment. Everyone’s on Zoom calls.” A lack of privacy or the chance to move to a different room is harder to bear when bars, cafés, and stores can’t offer an escape.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/covid-19-arch/Chayka-covid-home.jpg" alt="" width="839" height="629" /></p>
<p><strong>Office Space</strong></p>
<p>Covid-19 calls for prophylactic design. Masks and gloves barricade our bodies like a second skin. Taped circles spaced six feet apart make sure we don’t contaminate others while standing in line at the grocery store. A Dutch restaurant built greenhouse-like glass booths around its outdoor tables to shield diners and waitstaff from each other. A German café tested out hats with pool noodles attached so that guests would know not to get too close to one another. A casino in Florida installed a thick sneeze guard of plastic on its poker tables, with clearance on the bottom for players’ hands.</p>
<p>We’ll have to be hyper-aware of the infrastructure of cleanliness. Are people taking their shoes off at the door? Is there a place by the door where you wash your hands? Le Corbusier solved the last problem by installing a freestanding sink in the entryway of his Villa Savoye, from 1931.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/covid-19-arch/Chayka-covid-office.jpg" alt="" width="838" height="558" /></p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:54:41 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Green Architecture</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/green-architecture</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/green-architecture</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/greenarchitecture/http___cdn.cnn.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_200420123610-16b-green-buildings-around-the-world-restricted.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>Common Characteristics of a "Green" Building</strong></p>
<p>The highest goal of green architecture is to be fully sustainable. Simply put, people do "green" things in order to achieve sustainability. Some architecture, like <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/magney-house-by-glenn-murcutt-178002">Glenn Murcutt's 1984 Magney House,</a> has been an experiment in green design for years. While most green buildings do not have all of the following features, green architecture and design may include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ventilation systems designed for efficient heating and cooling</li>
<li>Energy-efficient lighting and appliances (e.g., <a href="https://www.energystar.gov/">ENERGY STAR</a><sup>®</sup> products)</li>
<li>Water-saving plumbing fixtures</li>
<li>Landscaping with native vegetation and planned to maximize passive solar energy</li>
<li>Minimal harm to the natural habitat</li>
<li>Alternative renewable energy power sources such as solar power or wind power</li>
<li>Non-synthetic, non-toxic materials used inside and out</li>
<li>Locally-obtained woods and stone, eliminating long-haul transportation</li>
<li>Responsibly-harvested woods</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/adaptive-reuse-repurposing-old-buildings-178242">Adaptive reuse</a> of older buildings</li>
<li>Use of recycled <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/about-architectural-antiquities-and-salvage-175958">architectural salvage</a></li>
<li>Efficient use of space</li>
<li>Optimal location on the land, maximizing sunlight, winds, and natural sheltering</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/greenarchitecture/http___cdn.cnn.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_200316120121-13-green-buildings-around-the-world.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><strong>Looking to a Sustainable Future</strong></p>
<p>Green design has many related names and concepts associated with it, besides sustainable development. Some people emphasize the ecology and have adopted names like eco-design, eco-friendly architecture, and even arcology. Eco-tourism is a 21st-century trend, even if <a href="https://fthmb.tqn.com/ogD4kpXNCKVsTyMuQPkSJZvM-FQ=/green-eco-527161822-crop-5a24c587beba330037243de6.jpg">eco house designs might appear to be a bit non-traditional</a>.</p>
<p>A building can look beautiful and even be constructed from very expensive materials, but not be "green." Likewise, a building can be very "green" but visually unappealing. How do we get good architecture? How do we move toward what Roman architect Vitruvius suggested to be the <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/the-rules-of-architecture-177224">three rules of architecture</a>—to be well-built, useful by serving a purpose, and beautiful to look at?</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/greenarchitecture/http___cdn.cnn.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_200420123610-16b-green-buildings-around-the-world-restricted.jpg" alt="" /></p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (დავით ნიკურაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:33:42 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Designing the STEM Learning Facilities of the Future</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/designing-the-stem-learning-facilities-of-the-future</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/designing-the-stem-learning-facilities-of-the-future</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/Designing-Workplaces-to-Increase-Motivation-and-Creativity-Hidden-influencers/skola-3.jpg" /></p>
<p>Schools are multiplying their STEM opportunities for students and training teachers to deliver STEM education—and also building and remodeling schools in support of new and emerging STEM programs.</p>
<p>The challenge for planners, architects, and educators is that STEM education curriculum and learning activities are constantly evolving.</p>
<p>How can we harness this moving target to inform our planning and design process? Architects and designers are rethinking the way they create modern educational spaces, putting student experience at the forefront of design.</p>
<p>To be effective, a new STEM facility must respond to a variety of learning activities, ever-changing technology, and the reality of having to make very detailed, specific, and often expensive design and construction decisions before a STEM curriculum is established.</p>
<p>In a perfect world, the STEM teachers would be identified, the curriculum set, and this would heavily influence the design process and outcome of the new STEM facility.</p>
<p>For remodeling existing buildings, it is more common to have the STEM teachers who will be teaching in the space actively involved with planning, design, and furniture and equipment selection.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">This blog will explore that concern, as well as offer insight for those who know exactly what they want to do in their spaces. </span></h4>
<p>When designing a STEM space it is important to consider the scope of practical learning that may occur.</p>
<p>Ideally, a STEM space is conducive to all learning activities and holds the infrastructure to support this.</p>
<p><strong>Examples of this infrastructure may include:</strong></p>
<p>- Wet Areas (wet flooring, sinks, taps)</p>
<p>- Fume Extraction - Accessible Power (overhead power for soldering etc.)</p>
<p>- Chroma Key wall - Testing Space (enclosed area)</p>
<p>- Fixed Recording Equipment.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Transparency-2.jpg" alt="" width="591" height="394" /></p>
<p><br />The best architects and designers of STEM spaces understand what real-life STEM programs look and sound like.</p>
<p>STEM Classrooms are adaptable, flexible, mobile and ergonomic.</p>
<p>STEM rooms can be noisy, exuberant classrooms where multiple right answers abound and failure is regarded as a positive step toward discovery and successful solutions.</p>
<p>Students work closely together; using hands-on methods to solve real-world problems … give them enough room to become creative, innovative, critical thinkers. <br /><br />Because STEM is generally an integrated project-based, problem-solving, inquiry learning programs, students need small-group areas to plan and discuss their projects.</p>
<p>STEM’s influence has literally changed how designers label classrooms. For example, in the past, classroom learning was separate from lab learning.</p>
<p>Today, the term “lab/classroom” is used to describe a combination space where students can move from discussion to hands-on work and back during a single class period. Research on designing STEM hubs show a minimum of 5.57 square meter per student and a maximum of 24 students is ideal.</p>
<p>Another important feature is student project spaces that are readily accessible from the science classrooms, as well as access to the outdoors.</p>
<p>That access is essential for students to test creations and display them, without the limitations of walls and ceilings. Ideally, “technology should be everywhere” in the STEM classroom. Tablet-type devices should travel with students and connect to a wireless network.</p>
<p>The engineering aspect of the program should include CAD with screens, printers (including 3D), and plotters. Connectively is key, digital devices are essential for students to be able to instantly connect with global data and other resources.</p>
<p>Optimised STEM classrooms allow students to have power for their computers or tablet devices, as well as Wi-Fi.</p>
<p>A few words about STEM Furniture: For maximum longevity, invest in furniture that is modular and sturdy. The extra cost – and functionality – is worth it.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Seating</span> </h4>
<p>The days of traditional, single-function classroom furniture are dwindling. The STEM classroom has students standing, sitting on stools, rolling on chairs, and casual lounging to collaborate. Above all, classroom seating must offer a range of movement, positions and functions.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Desks and Tables</span></h4>
<p>Project-based learning requires desks or tables capable of being arranged into compact pods that fit six to eight students. Having the flexibility and ability to rearrange the desk for uses in multiple ways is key.</p>
<p>For example, desktops that taper back to front (think pie shape) allow for a tight circle or individual arrangements. Table design and materials have certainly expanded to accommodate STEM.</p>
<p>Work surfaces can now stand up to chemicals and heat, and height varies, all without compromising a large work area and stability.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Storage</span></h4>
<p>Most of the student projects within the STEM environment will take place over more than one class period.</p>
<p>It’s essential to have space to safely leave or store in-progress projects. And, educators need mobile storage for organizing hands-on project materials and tools, as well as mobile units to house projectors and computers for presentations.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/21223_N93_medium.jpg" width="591" height="395" /></p>
<p>As a conclusion, architects and designers must become partners in creating the dynamic science teaching facilities required for STEM education, because STEM building should create a  hub for student, teacher and visitor activity while establishing front door for the high-profile program.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (სოფო კოტრიკაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 22:31:00 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Constructing smart homes for low-income families using Polystyrene</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/constructing-smart-homes-for-low-income-families-using-polystyrene</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/constructing-smart-homes-for-low-income-families-using-polystyrene</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/constructing-smart-homes/1-smart-house-baufritz-first-certified-self-sufficient-home-germany.jpg" /></p>
<p>Thatches, timbers, concrete blocks or cement and adobe bricks are no longer the only materials that can be used to build homes. New building projects, materials and technology have emerged.</p>
<p>Polystyrene can be used to build environmentally-friendly homes for low-income families that are residing in squalor settlements in urban areas.</p>
<p>With a proper building design, Polystyrene is an energy-efficient and climate-friendly building material. </p>
<p>Indeed, Polystyrene wall filler is very thermally efficient, and once its old structure is demolished, it can be recycled (Vincent, 2012:1).</p>
<p>It provides permanent insulation not only in walls but also in roofs and floors.</p>
<p>The design of low-cost smart homes using Polystyrene can effectively reduce and save governments and people the cost of building mass housing units by forty (40) percent than building them with conventional construction materials such as concrete, cement and sand (Jibo, 2013).</p>
<p>The design of Polystyrene with wire-mesh and sprayed with concrete provides quite a light structure that tolerates a lot of stress. The tolerant characteristic of Polystyrene makes it green and environmentally-friendly building material.</p>
<p>However, some experts are critically opposed to the use of Polystyrene in buildings i.e. a sandwich of Polystyrene and concrete can hardly be called green.</p>
<p>They opined that a significant problem with Polystyrene insulation, found almost universally in structural insulated panels (SIPs) and insulated concrete forms (ICFs) are full of the toxic fire retardant <em>hexabromocyclododecane </em>or HBDC (Alex, 2010; Lloyd et al, 2010).</p>
<p>In any case, ICFs are green and they save energy. A combination of ICFs and alternative nonfossil fuel-based substance(s) like rigid mineral wool and polyurethane, which does not contain toxic chemicals, would be perfect for building massive housing units for low-income families in cities and villages across the globe.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/constructing-smart-homes/1-smart-house-baufritz-first-certified-self-sufficient-home-germany.jpg" alt="" width="551" height="309" /></p>
<p>This picture is a simple bungalow home that is built with Polystyrene, which can comfortably be produced en masse to accommodate a plethora of urban and rural low-income families.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (სოფო კოტრიკაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 11:50:50 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Contemporary Architecture</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/contemporary-architecture</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/architecture/contemporary-architecture</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/steel-buildings-03-1.jpg" /></p>
<h4><strong><em><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/steel-buildings-03-1.jpg" alt="" width="992" height="558" /></em></strong></h4>
<p>The different styles and approaches have in common the use of very advanced technology and modern building materials, such as Tube structure which allows the construction of the buildings that are taller, lighter and stronger than those in the 20th century, and the use of new techniques of computer-aided design, which allow buildings to be designed and modeled on computers in three dimensions and constructed with more precision and speed. </p>
<p>Contemporary buildings and styles vary greatly. Some feature concrete structures wrapped in glass or aluminum screens, very asymmetric facades, and cantilevered sections that hang over the street.</p>
<p>Skyscrapers twist, or break into crystal-like facets. Facades are designed to shimmer or change color at different times of the day. </p>
<p>Whereas the major monuments of<span style="color: #000000;"> <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modern_architecture">modern architecture</a> i</span>n the 20th cent<span style="color: #000000;">ury were mostly concentrated in the United States and western Europe, contemporary architecture is global; important new buildings have been built in China, Russia, Latin America, and particularly in<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong> <a style="color: #000000; text-decoration: underline;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arab_states_of_the_Persian_Gulf">Arab states of the Persian Gulf</a>.</strong></span></span></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Features of Contemporary Architecture</span></h4>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Classicized ideas thrived on specific <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://developmentone.net/design-perspective/">design</a> elements. The have flourishes that are predictable and distinguishable while contemporary architecture is more flexible. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Contemporary architects thrive on sophisticated and innovative ideas. They deviate from traditions and norms. To achieve this, they need contemp</span>orary materials to create these ideas.</p>
<p>You will not only appreciate the innovative and creative designs in these buildings.</p>
<p>You will also understand the aesthetic feeling through the unique design of structures.</p>
<p>Moreover, contemporary architecture uses a vast range of building materials. These include concrete, glass, wood and aluminum screens. These materials add contrast and homogeneity.</p>
<p>For instance, you will notice they have oversize plate glass windows. These allow plenty of natural light and create large open spaces. They engender a sense of airiness, hence minimizing air conditioning costs.</p>
<p>Moreover, the building frames don't always follow symmetry and often have innovative shapes.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/143111_00_2x.jpg" alt="" width="996" height="664" /></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Tendency - The Sense of Sustainability</span></h4>
<p>The present is an era where global warming is a real issue. It is now essential to take specific measures to ensure nature is not compromised.</p>
<p>For this reason, modern architects design buildings that are energy efficient. This is in part thanks to recycled materials for the construction process.</p>
<p>This needs to include the use of solar panels for roofing purposes.</p>
<p>Moreover, the widespread use of reinforced concrete creates not only innovative ideas. It also enhances aesthetic appeal to most buildings.</p>
<p>These architects hope to achieve this idea. They’d want to do this to ensure that the whole project is economical.</p>
<p>They also want to focus on sustaining the end user’s needs.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/seun-city-walk-avoid-obvious-sustainability.jpg" alt="" width="969" height="683" /></p>
<p>A growing tendency in the 21st centu<span style="color: #000000;">ry is <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eco-architecture">eco-architecture</a>, also termed <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sustainable_architecture">sustainable architecture</a> buildings with features that conserve heat and energy, and sometimes produce their own energy through solar cells and windmills and use solar heat to generate <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solar_hot_water">solar hot water</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">They also may be built with their own <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wastewater">wastewater</a> treatment and sometimes<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong> <a style="color: #000000; text-decoration: underline;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rainwater_harvesting">rainwater harvesting</a></strong></span>. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Some buildings integrate gardens <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green_walls">green walls</a> and <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green_roofs">green roofs</a> into their structures. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Other features of eco-architecture include the use of wood and</span> recycled materials.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Architecture</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 21:58:51 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
