<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Spectrum - Sustainability</title>
		<description><![CDATA[სამშენებლო კომპანია, საპროექტო კომპანია, ინტერიერის დიზაინი, მშენებლობა, პროექტირება, დიზაინი]]></description>
		<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:08:26 +0400</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (Spectrum Website)</managingEditor>
		<item>
			<title>The importance of natural light in the interior</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/the-importance-of-natural-light-in-the-interior</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/the-importance-of-natural-light-in-the-interior</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/u3.jpg" /></p>
<h4><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/93702722_2509637722633205_5901002258287427584_o.jpg" alt="" width="826" height="542" /></h4>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Aesthetics:</span></h4>
<p>In terms of aesthetics, natural light does a better job of bringing out color than artificial light can.</p>
<p>To create a natural look in the home, use natural colors wherever you can.</p>
<p>Wooden floors and bookcases, tan-colored sofas and marble tabletops or tiles are all good options.</p>
<p>Just as in nature, the natural light of the sun will draw these colors out so that they look subtly wild and naturalistic, which in turn creates an environment that people tend to be comfortable and relaxed in.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/1550940360_loft-living-room-natural-lighting.jpg" alt="" width="825" height="485" /></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Mirror Effect:</span></h4>
<p>In order to increase the impact of natural light in a room is to make good use of mirrors as well as reflective objects.</p>
<p>They reflect light around the space, helping the whole environment to look bright, and have the added benefit (when placed well around the room) of making it look bigger and more spacious.</p>
<h4><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/jjagfsg.jpg" alt="" width="823" height="544" /></h4>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Skylight and TDDs:</span></h4>
<p>Another simple project is to have skylights, or Tubular Daylighting Devices (TDDs), installed in the home.</p>
<p>While a large skylight might let in a little too much sun, and be quite glary at various points in the day (and no one wants a room they can’t use for six hours of the day), TDDs are small, cylinder-shaped skylights that have diffused or glazed bottoms to prevent the full force of a sunbeam entering the room.</p>
<p>Instead, you simply have a natural glow, not unlike having a conventional light on during the day.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Make Spaces Bigger:</span></h4>
<p>One of the great inhibitors of natural light in a room is if the space is too small and narrow.</p>
<p>The more open a space can be, the lighter it will feel when natural light is flowing into space from all directions.</p>
<p>While natural light should be the focus, it’s important to use soft lighting to complement the natural light. Making good use of LED or fluorescent lighting (preferably with dimmers to control how bright they are) can help enormously in brightening up rooms when used strategically.</p>
<p>For example, there are likely to be areas in the room that natural light either can’t reach or can only reach at certain points of the day.</p>
<p>At other times, those spaces would have been sitting in the shadow, which doesn’t help build the ambiance of the room.</p>
<p>And, of course, once night rolls around, there’s very little natural lighting available at all. Soft lighting can ‘fill’ the shadows and keep the room lit at night.</p>
<p>It’s preferable to have a large number of small lights spaced strategically around the room as well as the single, overbearing light in the center of the room.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Sustainability</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 11:07:14 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Benefits of Green Home</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/benefits-of-green-home</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/benefits-of-green-home</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/green-home.jpg" /></p>
<p>So, let’s compare green homes and discuss the factors that the buyers need to keep in mind while looking for green homes.</p>
<p>Green homes do not only refer to the green environment rather green homes refers to the effective use of environmental resources such as water, power, use of solar-based or power-based resources, encouraging rainwater harvesting techniques, use of garbage for composting and minimizing pollution.</p>
<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/8779_image1.jpg" alt="" width="822" height="549" /></p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Cost Factor</span></h4>
<p>Now let’s understand the cost factor. The price of property generally depends on factors like construction cost, location and as per the experts, there is no additional cost involved in building a green home.</p>
<p>The total cost of owning a green home can be equal or cheaper than regular homes. However, the green home might come as a bit expensive at the initial stage because of the investments like solar panels, disposable systems among other but in the long run, these investment become cost-effective as these require little maintenance, decrease the utility bills which help in cutting down in regular expenses.</p>
<p>Further, there are alternative materials to build green homes that fit one’s budget.</p>
<p>Most of the time, it has been seen that the cost of a green home comes equally to that of a standard home. And green homes come with several benefits also apart from offering a healthy environment.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Healthy home</span></h4>
<p>As green homes are generally made using toxin-free building materials, they offer a healthier environment as well as helps in fighting indoor pollution also.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Impact on the environment</span></h4>
<p>By adopting the concept of green homes, one is actually going closer to the environment by conserving the ecosystem and biodiversity, improving water and air quality, generating less waste and preserving natural resources.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Economical</span></h4>
<p>In the long run, green homes are economical because using renewable sources like hydropower, wind power, solar power one can actually cut on utility bills.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">LEED Rating</span></h4>
<p>Moreover, one needs to remember a few things while buying a green home such as the LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) rating, which is a globally-recognized system for certifying green buildings.</p>
<p>But if one has a regular house then also later it can be modified into an eco-friendly home because the common factors that work in both the cases include energy efficiency, water conservation, preservation of natural resources, generating less waste and maintaining a healthy neighborhood.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Sustainability</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 14:28:11 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Indoor Spaces-Polluted Air Alarms to Consider</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/indoor-spaces-polluted-air-alarms-to-consider</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/indoor-spaces-polluted-air-alarms-to-consider</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/buckhorn-place-burgers-architecture-house-whistler-canada_dezeen_2364_col_48.jpg" /></p>
<p>For prolonged exposure, this can cause lung, respiratory and cardiovascular disorders.</p>
<p>In Europe alone, around 400,000 people have died prematurely in 2014 due to polluted air (European Environment Agency, Air Quality in Europe, 2017 report).</p>
<p>Not everyone is aware that particulate matter and chemical byproducts arise indoors on a continuous basis.</p>
<p>This can come from various sources like cleaning products, aerosol cans, cooking, wood stoves, cigarette smoke, renovation, paint, dust movement, contaminated outdoor air.</p>
<p>Today’s houses are very well insulated for good reasons since we need to be energy-efficient.</p>
<p>But in case of insufficient ventilation, fungi can quickly emerge. In the summer opening a window is therefore highly recommended provided the outside air is clean, but in winter this is of course not always convenient.</p>
<p>With an air purifier you can always breathe healthy air, also when proper ventilation is not possible.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Sustainability</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 17:19:50 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Can be Learned from COVID-19 Pandemic?</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/what-can-be-learned-from-covid-19-pandemic-how-to-adopt-and-design-cities-accordingly</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/what-can-be-learned-from-covid-19-pandemic-how-to-adopt-and-design-cities-accordingly</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Presentation3.jpg" /></p>
<p>The new pandemic has brought fast changes like the dramatic shift from offices to home, global self-isolation What lessons should be learned and how designing cities and buildings should be reimagined according to the current pandemic?</p>
<p>What are the new guidelines to employ to better respond and handle similar conditions with less impact on human health and the economy? There is a lot written and discussed the issue, the need for changes and adaptation, so here are brought a few aspects of it:</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Configurability </span></h4>
<p>With <strong>COVID-19</strong> we have seen how different types of buildings and public spaces are being used for handling patients as the existing number of hospitals is far more than scarce.</p>
<p>Thus, in the nearest future while designing buildings one of the aspects might be its adaptability for other needs and uses like in case of an epidemic. </p>
<p>In addition, hospitals should be better designed for outbreaks.</p>
<p>What came to light during this pandemic is the inability of current hospital systems worldwide to accommodate the number of sick people.</p>
<p>In addition,  hospitals should have the availability of transforming rooms to limit the spread of viruses.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Consideration of virus-free transits </span></h4>
<p>As we have seen the major Lockdown of airports and high risks of spreading viruses, for the future, there is the need of rethinking security check procedures, in order to eliminate crowded lines, reduced wait time, and face-to-face contact from gates to board.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Air-quality Treatment </span></h4>
<p>From public transportation to hospital waiting areas, pharmacies, hypermarkets and public spaces, air quality control should be happening so to prevent virus spreading. </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19</strong> has shown us once again what risks people are facing while standing in a line for medicines, products or waiting to get healthcare service.</p>
<p>The certain elements that exist in health-care may be adopted to public spaces as well. Like limiting flat surfaces where germs can sit or installing ventilation systems that remove away contaminated air from any given area.</p>
<p>In addition, using antibacterial fabrics and finishes should be part of the development.</p>
<p>People spend more than 90% of their time indoors, therefore buildings and transportation systems should support well-being and risk-free stay.</p>
<p>Bringing fresh air into buildings minimizes the risk and time being exposed to viruses.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Future technologies and AI</span></h4>
<p>Integrating future technologies into buildings can be a tool to decrease risks.</p>
<p>The sensors that detect viruses can be used as the mechanism of temperature screening. This can be used starting from big enterprises to public areas to mitigate risks.</p>
<p>The real-time measurements of air quality informing visitors and representatives of the companies can help raise awareness of the importance of fresh air quality and at the same time well reduce the contamination risks. </p>
<p>Simpler methods can include limiting physical contact with the help of automation- like automated doors, voice-activated elevators and cell-phone controlled entries for hotel rooms, RFID technologies for making purchases, etc.   </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Recreational  and open spaces</span></h4>
<p>The importance of recreational places is not new, but now the possibility of entering recreational places with distancing is impossible.</p>
<p>The concerns about future viruses should encourage architects to design buildings with more open places that enable people to spread and adding more outdoor places even in skyscrapers.</p>
<p>Spending more time outdoors and having more greenery helps improve health and mental well-being and reduces air-pollution at the same time.</p>
<p>Its noteworthy that not having enough parks leads to no “escape” during the pandemic. </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Ability to wash hands</span></h4>
<p>Starting from retails stores to public areas and crowded streets –there should be the ability to wash hands properly.</p>
<p>In some countries temporary hand-washing stations are added to bus stops, so that passenger wash their hands before entering the transport.</p>
<p>Such practice should be deployed everywhere starting from stadiums to areas of tourist attractions.</p>
<p>What is for sure, conclusions should be drawn and improvements made in different aspects starting from public health to infrastructure and design.</p>
<p>There’s a lot that can be done, the above-mentioned points are quite a few.</p>
<p>And it is clear that the way we interact in large public spaces airports, hotels, hospitals, gyms, offices, hypermarkets, etc. should be improved, rethought and redesigned.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Sustainability</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 16:45:36 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Designing Workplaces to Increase Motivation and Creativity - Hidden influencers</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/designing-workplaces-to-increase-motivation-and-creativity-hidden-influencers</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/designing-workplaces-to-increase-motivation-and-creativity-hidden-influencers</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/waiting-area-office-design-by-oktra_2640x1980_acf_cropped-880x660.jpg" /></p>
<p>While a lot has been written and discussed how workplace design affects employees, there’s not much done or changed, and if so only in terms of design as its direct understanding.</p>
<p>Having offices well designed, with spaces to cooperate and relax is one approach, but at the same time what is not seen, but really influences our employees should not be underestimated.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Air Quality</span></h4>
<p>Various studies have been conducted and reflect the influence of polluted air on our health and general well-being.</p>
<p>A recent study by teams from Harvard and Syracuse Universities found that when ventilation was improved, and levels of carbon dioxide and emissions were reduced, employees performed 61% better on cognitive tasks.</p>
<p>Another study conducted on so-called “green” buildings found employees had 30% fewer headaches and respiratory complaints and performed about 27% better on cognitive tasks. They even slept better at night.</p>
<p>It’s noteworthy that air in the building is from 10 to 30 more polluted than the air outside, add the lack of oxygen especially in coworking spaces where there is no proper ventilation.</p>
<p>At <strong>Spectrum</strong> in line with the proper ventilation systems that filter air we use portable air purifiers to ensure the best air quality throughout the day. Also, the air is systematically monitored and checked for oxygen percentage and pollutants in the air. </p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Light</span></h4>
<p>There are various studies that link proper lighting to productivity. Besides the effect insufficient or bad quality light has on our eyesight it might be the reason for headaches, irritation, or decreased motivation.</p>
<p>Having designed offices with the availability of daylight is of great importance.</p>
<p>There are studies that link natural light to employees’ positive attitude, increased energy levels and decreased stress.</p>
<p>In addition consider having modern, good quality LED lighting to prevent eyes from straining.</p>
<h4><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/1_nWk3XjlxSIVbrrNbJ4GZgw.png" alt="" width="510" height="289" /><br /><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Greenery</span></h4>
<p>Greenery is also a good source of oxygen, some spaces are especially good for air filtration and also balancing humidity. It works positively on employees’ moods and decreases stress and improves the ability of concentration according to various studies.</p>
<p>At<strong> Spectrum</strong>, both, employees and visitors love to see the green wall from plants that just adds joy and freshness to design, but also cleans the air and supports employees’ positive mood.</p>
<p>Besides, every employee once joining Spectrum’s team is gifted a plant that he/she takes care of on a daily bases that bring more commitment and positivity into the office.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Break Areas-Open spaces</span></h4>
<p>Having the areas to take a break from the working environment is a good option, but also consider,  using open/outdoor spaces purposefully.</p>
<h4><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/be57d5e363dff8c1f3bad5f94abb1af5.jpg" alt="" width="526" height="324" /><br /><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Material Selection</span></h4>
<p>When planning a repair for the office being tempted to save on quality materials is easy. But keep in mind, that in a long run employee health will be affected with hazardous materials and VOCs from them in the air.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Ergonomic Furniture</span></h4>
<p>Having ergonomic furniture should be one of the prior considerations for the workplace appliance list. Ergonomic seating reduces stress, supports posture, is more comfortable, reduces the risk of neck problems and neck pain, and in total makes working easier.</p>
<h4><span style="font-size: 14pt;">Energy-efficiency and Environment </span></h4>
<p>Finally, taking care of the environment, bringing positive impact, should be one of the priorities of businesses, as in the long run we are all affected.  </p>
<p>Using materials that save energy, are not pollutants and are recyclable should be part of CSR.</p>
<p>This can start from the design process to choose proper materials, to select LED lighting, energy-efficient appliances and continue to the corporate culture where recycling, saving energy and positive blueprint is part of everyday life. </p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (თინა წივწივაძე)</author>
			<category>Sustainability</category>
			<pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 14:22:24 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sustainable Architectural Design of Kano City Walls and Gates</title>
			<link>https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/sustainable-architectural-design-of-kano-city-walls-and-gates</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://spectrum.ge/stories/sustainability/sustainable-architectural-design-of-kano-city-walls-and-gates</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/lowimg_1033.jpg" /></p>
<p>They were served with loopholes, moats, iron gates and many other defensive devices (Sule 2009). The mode of construction of these city walls was very different from the remnants of earth heaps that we observe today.</p>
<p>The importance of Kano city walls was clear in that they were defensive structures that signify a certain aspect of local developments in the era.</p>
<p>They also represented big public projects requiring sustainable and large-scale organization, skill and expertise, adequate resource mobilization and capacity, and commitment for big project delivery and continuity through various administrations spanning seven hundred years.</p>
<p>Sule (2009) highlighted the eyewitness accounts of Kano city walls and gates and observed that the maintenance and rehabilitation culture exemplified in the management of the walls is also greatly impressive as many colonial reports testify, especially in the first half of the 20<sup>th</sup> century.</p>
<p>The rehabilitation of the city wall (Ganuwa) was solely achieved using sustainable local indigenous building materials in the form of earth, wrought iron, leather and timber.</p>
<p>This, according to Sule, is a great lesson in the art of self-reliance. However, this attempt, in my view, was to bring together as well as revive local building construction technology and professionalism, which is another aspect that needs much investigation and further research (Jibo 2011).</p>
<p>E.W. Bovill, a colonial military official resident in Kano for a number of years, became greatly acquainted with the quotidian commercial functions of the city, particularly to the rest of West Africa, as well as North Africa.</p>
<p>His descriptions of the teeming commercial life inside the great city walls and the crowd which thronged the daily market signify that, in addition to being a center of learning, Kano was a cosmopolitan city and local, as well as the intra-and interregional center of trade.</p>
<p>Basil Davidson, in The Black Man’s Burden: Africa And The Curse of The Nation-State, stated that he viewed the Kano City Wall in 1941, while in transit to Egypt during the 2<sup>nd</sup> World War when they stopped over at Kano to refuel.</p>
<p>The Wall, he said, stood sharp contrast to the claims that Africa had no history to which they had been subjected at home. He explained this as his “life work” which, in his opinion, was originally “trying to understand and tell truths” to the historians who claim that Africa has no history.</p>
<p>Therefore, the fact these two British citizens who served in the British imperial army were so greatly influenced by the evidence of Kano’s development, is a great testimony to the enduring influences of Kano’s historical monuments.</p>
<p>The city walls, as indicated in the work of Aliyu (2009), represent a clear picture of a real expansion of the city since between the12<sup>th</sup> and 16<sup>th</sup> centuries. They defended Kano’s inhabitants against a multitude of foes. If there were no great Kano walls, the city may have been eliminated from the history of Africa or reduced to an insignificant town on the contemporary map of Africa.</p>
<p>The Kano wall is therefore perhaps the largest public works project in Africa that brought together every member of the community: the rich, the poor, scholars, artisans, slaves, etc.</p>
<p>The cooperation exhibited by the ancient people of Kano paid them well in the security, stability and continuity of the statehood that Kano attained. <br /><br /><img src="https://spectrum.ge/images/Blog/7ef8828bee4a721f5a975ef088814589.jpg" alt="" width="713" height="475" /></p>
<p>A renovated Kano City Wall almost to completion. The clay mortar is used to render the overhead course.</p>]]></description>
			<author>tinatin.tsivtsivadze@spectrum.ge (სოფო კოტრიკაძე)</author>
			<category>Sustainability</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 02:12:33 +0400</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
